<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-18T14:26:27-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">FtBotB - The Postman</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/18/The-Postman/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FtBotB - The Postman" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/18/The-Postman</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/18/The-Postman/"><![CDATA[<div>


<div class="container" style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <a href="/assets/images/ezwatti.png" data-toggle="lightbox" data-title="">
        <img class="container post-image" alt="" src="/assets/images/ezwatti.png" />

    </a>
    <div class="container figure-caption" style="margin-top: -16px !important; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 16px">
        
    </div>
</div>

</div>

<h2 id="from-the-back-of-the-book">From the Back of the Book:</h2>
<h2 id="working-title">Working Title:</h2>
<p>The Postman</p>
<h2 id="story-synopsis">Story Synopsis:</h2>
<p>Ezwatti Levar has dedicated his life to being a postman for the Interstellar Postal Service, an organization founded to facilitate communication and trade between the many inhabited planets across the galaxy. Though interstellar travel is commonplace in this era, reliably delivering messages and goods across astronomical distances remains a monumental challenge, one that the neutral Interstellar Postal Service seeks to overcome. Ezwatti finds purpose and takes pride in being part of this vital network that connects the disparate planetary colonies, providing a lifeline for countless worlds. However, everything changes when mounting political tensions between Earth and several alien civilizations erupt into all-out war. As battles rage across space and essential supply lines are disrupted, Ezwatti watches in dismay as the ISPS comes under threat. If the combatants lose faith in the postal service’s neutrality, its couriers could become targets, and the entire system risks collapsing. Driven by patriotic loyalty, Ezwatti decides to secretly intercept and divert crucial enemy communications to his government on Earth. He hopes this inside information will help turn the tide of the war in humanity’s favor. While already risky, his unsanctioned espionage mission becomes even more dangerous when he’s caught by enemy forces. Subjected to brutal interrogation, Ezwatti refuses to crack and reveal his agenda. But his captors eventually uncover enough evidence to realize the bigger implications of his actions - the diplomatic fallout now endangering ISPS neutrality and making couriers spies in the eyes of the enemy. This grave mistake exposes the magnitude of his miscalculation, as he realizes the jeopardy he’s brought not only upon himself but also upon the thousands of other couriers who form the backbone of the interstellar postal system. His actions have single handily, inadvertently threatened the very existence of this vital lifeline, turning couriers across the galaxy into targets amid a war where information is just as critical as firepower. Ezwatti is wracked with guilt over this unintentional consequence, knowing he’s jeopardized not just his own safety but that of postal workers everywhere. Yet despite the personal stakes, he remains steadfastly committed to his duty and finds a way to escape captivity. Now a fugitive behind enemy lines, he perseveres in delivering his stolen intelligence to Earth, determined to see his mission through to the end. With political tensions continuing to mount, ripple effects from Ezwatti’s actions call into question the ISPS’s once-sacrosanct neutrality. As governments start seeing postal couriers more as information operatives than neutral parties, their safety can no longer be guaranteed, even as the service’s role keeps growing more vital amidst wartime disruption. Ezwatti remains a soldier for Earth’s cause, knowing he still has a critical role to play for his people, even on the run with his life constantly at risk. But he also grieves the loss of innocence for his beloved ISPS, and the dream of impartial exchange and communication he always stood for. As the fate of the entire galaxy hangs in the balance, Ezwatti struggles to reconcile his loyalty to country with his devotion to the ideals of the Interstellar Postal Service.</p>

<h2 id="questions">Questions:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Would you purchase and read this novel if you saw it in a bookstore?</li>
  <li>Would you read this novel if it were given to you as a gift?</li>
  <li>How do you feel after having read the synopsis?</li>
  <li>What is your overall opinion of the genre?</li>
  <li>Have you ever read a novel space adventure before?</li>
</ol>

<p>Drop me a comment down below!</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="FtBotB" /><category term="FtBotB" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've crafted a science fiction narrative about Ezwatti Levar, a postal worker whose loyalty to Earth compromises the neutrality of the Interstellar Postal Service during an interstellar war. Through Ezwatti's story, I explore themes of duty versus ethics, examining how one person's choices can have far-reaching consequences. His decision to spy for Earth while maintaining his postal duties raises questions about neutrality in wartime and the true cost of patriotism, ultimately threatening the vital communication network that connects humanity's colonies across the galaxy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beat of the Day - Applied Phlebotium</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/11/18/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Applied-Phlebotium/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beat of the Day - Applied Phlebotium" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/11/18/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Applied-Phlebotium</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/11/18/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Applied-Phlebotium/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="applied-phlebotinum">Applied Phlebotinum:</h3>
<p>Phlebotinum is the versatile substance that may be rubbed on anything to cause an effect needed by a plot.</p>

<h3 id="examples-include-but-are-not-limited-to">Examples include but are not limited to:</h3>
<p>Nanotechnology, magic crystal emanations, pixie dust, and Green Rocks. In essence, it is plot fuel. Without it, the story would grind to an abrupt halt. It’s the science that powers the FTL drive on the starship so the characters can get somewhere, it’s the magic that hatches the Egg MacGuffin so the protagonist can save an endangered species, it’s the strange things unknown to science or magic that do basically anything except those limits and dangers required by the plot. The reader does not know how Phlebotinum would work and the creators hope nobody cares. In essence, it’s a plot device that abstracts away the problem of hard science.</p>

<h3 id="best-practice">Best Practice:</h3>
<p>Consistency is key. While Phlebotinum doesn’t need to be scientifically explained, it should follow consistent rules within your story. For Aetheric Crystals:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Establish clear limitations (e.g., they become unstable if overused)</li>
  <li>Define specific applications and stick to them</li>
  <li>Create plot-relevant drawbacks or risks</li>
</ul>

<p>By maintaining consistency, you keep the story engaging without frustrating readers with arbitrary changes to how the Phlebotinum works.</p>

<p>How do you feel about this particular beat? Would you use it in your story? Drop me a comment down below.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="BotD" /><category term="BotD" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I explore the concept of Phlebotinum - those versatile plot devices like nanotechnology or magic crystals that help move stories forward without getting bogged down in hard science explanations. While these elements don't need rigorous scientific justification, I emphasize the importance of establishing consistent rules and limitations within your story world to maintain reader engagement. Whether it's Aetheric Crystals or Green Rocks, these tools can serve as effective plot fuel when used thoughtfully and consistently.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FtBotB - Earth Ship</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/18/Earth-Ship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FtBotB - Earth Ship" /><published>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/18/Earth-Ship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/18/Earth-Ship/"><![CDATA[<div>


<div class="container" style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <a href="/assets/images/ship.png" data-toggle="lightbox" data-title="">
        <img class="container post-image" alt="" src="/assets/images/ship.png" />

    </a>
    <div class="container figure-caption" style="margin-top: -16px !important; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 16px">
        
    </div>
</div>

</div>

<h2 id="from-the-back-of-the-book">From the Back of the Book:</h2>
<h2 id="working-title">Working Title:</h2>
<p>Earth Ship</p>

<h2 id="story-synopsis">Story Synopsis:</h2>
<p>The year is 2954. After many decades of environmental decline, humanity has finally achieved the unthinkable - technology capable of artificially maintaining Earth’s atmosphere and temperature no matter where in the universe the planet is located. No longer dependent on the Sun’s warmth and light, the Earth itself has been transformed into a colossal spaceship, ready to voyage into the cosmic unknown. Brilliant scientist Dr. Avigayil Gray has been appointed Captain of the Earth Ship. Though ambitious and headstrong, Avigayil’s controversial ideas of planetary migration have won her few friends among the mission’s scientists and engineers. Her most vocal critic is renowned astrophysicist Dr. Vikram Milovanović, who believes that tampering with the Earth’s natural relationship with the Sun is at best, reckless narcissism and at worst, dangerous hubris. As the launch date nears, Avigayil and Vikram’s professional antagonism erupts into a passionate argument and discontinue their working relationship. Launch day goes off without a hitch and months later, they had cleared the Milky Way. Things continue to progress nicely for the next sixteen-months. However, on the seventeenth-month of the journey, a catastrophic systems failure causes a radiation leak and utter chaos, as the Earth Ship is hurtled off-course into uncharted space. Cut off from the Sun and lost in the void, the planet’s artificial life support begins to steadily fail. As food and water supplies dwindle, Avigayil and Vikram must put aside their differences to find a way to save the Earth ship. Desperate, they initiate an experimental procedure, channeling the Earth’s internal heat to repower the engines and get critical support systems back online. The maneuver is successful, but has an unforeseen side effect, as the planet’s molten core becomes dangerously unstable. With worldwide volcanic eruptions and tectonic shifts imminent, society descends into chaos. Avigayil and Vikram, having no time to restore the Earth to its original orbit, they decide to attempt to find a habitable planet to settle before the end comes for them all. With annihilation looming, Avigayil comes to realize that her faith in science alone is not enough. If humanity is to survive, the wisdom of Vikram and others must balance her own relentless ambition. In this crucible among the stars, Avigayil and Vikram find that only together can they pilot the Earth Ship to safety and forge a hopeful future for humankind.</p>

<h2 id="questions">Questions:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Would you purchase and read this novel if you saw it in a bookstore?</li>
  <li>Would you read this novel if it were given to you as a gift?</li>
  <li>How do you feel after having read the synopsis?</li>
  <li>What is your overall opinion of the genre?</li>
  <li>Have you ever read a novel space opera before?</li>
</ol>

<p>Drop me a comment down below!</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="FtBotB" /><category term="FtBotB" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've developed a sci-fi narrative about Earth's transformation into an interstellar vessel under the leadership of Dr. Avigayil Gray and her rival Dr. Vikram Milovanović. Through their conflict over humanity's technological ambitions and subsequent forced collaboration when disaster strikes, I explore themes of scientific hubris versus caution. As Earth faces destruction from its own unstable core, these opposing viewpoints must find balance to ensure humanity's survival among the stars.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today’s Thoughts</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/11/15/Today's-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today’s Thoughts" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/11/15/Today's-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/11/15/Today's-Thoughts/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="my-positives">My Positives:</h2>
<p>I’ve posted six new posts today, and I am hopeful that I will reach one-hundred posts today so that I can take the site live finally.
I drank all of my coffee this morning.
It’s been an okay pain day thus far.
I gave myself grace yesterday and only posted what I could, which ended up being three posts.
I am getting the hang of webstorm the more I use it.</p>

<h2 id="my-negatives">My Negatives:</h2>
<p>I haven’t eaten anything by mouth yet today.</p>

<h2 id="my-thoughts-on-today">My Thoughts on Today:</h2>
<p>I am overall in a good mood today. I’m also having a decent pain day. Here’s to tomorrow being as good as today or better.</p>

<h3 id="questions-to-consider">Questions to Consider:</h3>
<p>What are your thoughts about today?<br />
What are your negatives regarding today?<br />
What are your positives regarding today?</p>

<p>Drop me a comment down below.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this daily reflection post, I share both the challenges and bright moments of my day. Despite dealing with chronic pain, late starts, and worried moments, I found joy in unexpected places - like some meaningful progress with my work. I'm learning to acknowledge both the ups and downs, celebrating small victories like posting content even when I don't feel like doing it. This kind of honest daily check-in helps me stay grounded and might become a regular feature of my blog.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some Advice</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/2024/11/15/Some-Advice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Advice" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/2024/11/15/Some-Advice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/2024/11/15/Some-Advice/"><![CDATA[<p>Stop for a moment and enjoy being a beginner.</p>

<p>Do everything in your power to soak it all up.</p>

<p>Because I promise you this, the higher you climb, the more successful you get, the harder it gets to feel your next growth spurt.</p>

<p>After all, being a beginner is easy. That’s why everyone wants to pick something different as soon as things start to even remotely get hard.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I reflect on the unique value of being a beginner in your craft. While many rush to move beyond this stage as soon as challenges arise, I emphasize how the early learning phase offers special opportunities for growth and development that become rarer as you advance. I encourage writers to embrace and appreciate their beginner status, as each new level of mastery makes transformative growth spurts increasingly difficult to achieve.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FtBotB - An Extinction Level Event</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/15/FtBotB-Plummeting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FtBotB - An Extinction Level Event" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/15/FtBotB-Plummeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/ftbotb/2024/11/15/FtBotB-Plummeting/"><![CDATA[<div>


<div class="container" style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <a href="/assets/images/plummet.png" data-toggle="lightbox" data-title="">
        <img class="container post-image" alt="" src="/assets/images/plummet.png" />

    </a>
    <div class="container figure-caption" style="margin-top: -16px !important; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 16px">
        
    </div>
</div>

</div>

<h3 id="from-the-back-of-the-book">From the Back of the Book:</h3>
<h3 id="working-title">Working Title:</h3>
<p>Plummeting</p>

<h3 id="story-synopsis">Story Synopsis:</h3>
<p>Eyvǫra Naldi gazes out the airplane window with a sense of foreboding. Below, the once-vibrant city of Atlanta is now shrouded in an ominous gray haze. She shudders as the memories flooded back - the brilliant flash of light as the asteroid hit, the ensuing firestorm that engulfed entire neighborhoods in an instant. Now, hours after the cataclysmic impact, Eyvǫra and the three-hundred and eighty-five other passengers aboard American Air Flight 671 are left circling endlessly above the ruined city. With the airport tower eerily silent and fuel tanks dwindling, the panicked passengers debate their fate. Should they attempt a risky emergency landing with no way to assess the tower control due to the devastation below or stay airborne until the engines gave out, sacrificing themselves in a doomed nosedive? As anxieties reach a fever pitch, Eyvǫra takes charge. She rallies the passengers with an impassioned speech, convincing them to take their chances with a landing. Moved by her courage, the passengers steel themselves as the aircraft descends toward a barren field adjacent to the airport tarmac. The landing gear screeches against the ragged earth as the plane touches down. Now safely on the ground, but enveloped in the strange haze, Eyvǫra and the shell-shocked passengers disembark to face the nightmare laid before them. Atlanta, once a vibrant metropolis, is now smoldering ruins as far as the eye could see. With communications gone and supplies dwindling, the group struggle to survive in the post-apocalyptic wasteland. Eyvǫra emerges as a leader, scavenging food and organizing teams to care for the injured. However, tensions flare as terror and hunger set in. Eyvǫra knows their only hope is banding together. Can she keep the group unified long enough to withstand this brave new world? Their ultimate fate will test the limits of the human spirit in the face of unthinkable tragedy.</p>

<h3 id="questions">Questions:</h3>
<ol>
  <li>Would you purchase and read this novel if you saw it in a bookstore?</li>
  <li>Would you read this novel if it were given to you as a gift?</li>
  <li>How do you feel after having read the synopsis?</li>
  <li>What is your overall opinion of the genre?</li>
  <li>Have you ever read a book that is all about an extinction level event before?</li>
</ol>

<p>Drop me a comment down below!</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="FtBotB" /><category term="FtBotB" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I've developed a post-apocalyptic survival story focused on Eyvǫra Naldi and 385 other passengers stranded in the air above a devastated Atlanta after an asteroid impact. The synopsis follows their harrowing decision to attempt a landing and subsequent struggle to survive in the ruined city. Through Eyvǫra's emergence as a leader, I explore themes of human resilience and group dynamics in the face of catastrophe. The story asks whether unity can prevail when civilization crumbles.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Internal Conflict - An Exercise:</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/Internal-Conflict/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Internal Conflict - An Exercise:" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/Internal-Conflict</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/Internal-Conflict/"><![CDATA[<p>Identifying Your Character’s Internal Conflict:<br />
A character traversing a change arc will have one overarching internal struggle that will plague them
throughout the story. Because they’ll have to acknowledge and settle this inner conflict to achieve success, it’s
vital to know what it is. It can stem from various sources, so use this tool to brainstorm options.</p>

<p>To identify the character’s main internal conflict, establish key pieces of their arc:<br />
Emotional Wound: What traumatic event from the past still haunts your character?<br />
Outer Motivation: What is your character’s main story goal?<br />
Inner Motivation: What missing need will be met by achieving that goal?<br />
To deepen the story, look for places where certain factors might clash (driving the members of your story’s
cast apart) or, alternatively, create common ground to bring them together.</p>

<p>Emotional Wound:<br />
Outer Motivation:<br />
Inner Motivation:<br />
Inner Conflict:</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="exercise" /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a tool to help writers identify their characters' core internal conflicts by examining the interplay between emotional wounds, outer goals, and inner needs. By understanding how past trauma shapes current motivations, writers can develop more compelling character arcs. This framework helps uncover the deeper psychological struggles that drive character growth and plot development.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Character Arc Progression - An Exercise:</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/Character-Arc-Progression/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Character Arc Progression - An Exercise:" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/Character-Arc-Progression</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/Character-Arc-Progression/"><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to poignant character elements, none are quite as formative as the wounding event. It
generates crippling fears, changes the way the character views herself and the world, and spawns unhealthy
coping mechanisms that do more harm than good—all of which results in someone who is stuck in
dysfunction, with contentment and fulfillment perpetually beyond their grasp. This is where your story, and
the character’s arc, begins.</p>

<p>But what, you might ask, does the wound have to do with character arc? How does it all fit together?
Allow us to introduce the Character Arc Progression tool—a streamlined flowchart that uses the wound and
its aftereffects to help you figure out what basic need your character is missing because of the wounding
event, the story goal they’ll pursue in order to fill that lack, likely sources of conflict to impede their progress,
and much more. Using the questions below, start anywhere on the flowchart and fill in the missing pieces as
you discover them.</p>

<p>Questions to Consider</p>

<p>Outer Motivation: What outer motivation (story goal) is your character pursuing to try and attain her inner
motivation?</p>

<p>Inner Motivation: Which of the 5 basic human needs is your character missing due to the wounding event
and its aftereffects?</p>

<p>Physiological: the most basic and primal needs, such as food, water, shelter, sleep, and reproductive
sex.</p>

<p>Safety and Security: the need to be safe, in good health, and have stability, both for oneself and loved
ones.</p>

<p>Love and Belonging: tied to human connection and the ability to form lasting bonds, experience
intimacy, feel love, and love others in turn.</p>

<p>Esteem and Recognition: the need to be valued, appreciated, and recognized by others for one’s
contributions, as well as to achieve higher levels of worthiness, self-respect, and confidence.</p>

<p>Self-Actualization: the need to attain fulfillment through the realization of one’s potential. This might
come in the form of pursuing and achieving meaningful goals, seeking knowledge, attaining spiritual
enlightenment, or embracing core values, beliefs, and an identity so one may live one’s truth.</p>

<p>Outer Conflict: What external forces (people, organizations, natural or supernatural phenomena, etc.) are
blocking your character from achieving her outer motivation?</p>

<p>Inner Conflict: What internal difficulties (doubts, temptations, secrets, moral dilemmas, flaws that thwart
success, opposing desires or goals, etc.) are making it hard for your character to achieve her outer motivation?</p>

<p>The Lie: What dis-empowering and false belief (No one could ever love me; I can’t trust my own instincts;
People are inherently evil, etc.) does the character now embrace because of the wounding event? This could
be a belief about herself, an organization, a certain group of people, or the world at large.</p>

<p>Wound: What traumatic past experience caused the character deep psychological pain that continues to
significantly impair her into the present?</p>

<p>Fear: What specific fear resulted from the wounding event that is now driving the character’s behavior?</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="exercise" /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This framework is for understanding how character wounds shape story arcs. By examining the relationship between traumatic past events and current behaviors, we can trace how wounds generate fears, false beliefs, and dysfunctional coping mechanisms. I provide targeted questions to help writers identify their characters' basic human needs, motivations, and conflicts that stem from these formative wounds. This flowchart approach helps create more psychologically complex character arcs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Scene Card - An Exercise</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/A-Scene-Card/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Scene Card - An Exercise" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/A-Scene-Card</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/exercise/2024/11/15/A-Scene-Card/"><![CDATA[<p>Do you want to create more illustrative scenes?</p>

<p>Challenge the character in some way (eg. their assumptions, their skills, their compassion, their bravery etc. - it’s hard to gauge someone’s strengths and weaknesses until you see how they handle challenges). Show the character making a conscious or instinctive decision about how to behave. Show the character in another environment (compared to previous scenes) - we act differently round our buddies than we do at work, and we act different when we are in charge than when we are the subordinate (show us a new aspect of the character). Lastly, show the character in a similar scene to previously but making a different choice to last time - if it’s apparent why there’s a change this either shows complexity of character or character growth.</p>

<p>Do you want to create less illustrative scenes?</p>

<p>Tell us about the character rather than showing us (a little telling here and there is inevitable but it does not substitute for stronger scenes showing us character). Involve the character as a mere spectator, or simply following the guidance/orders of others. Tell us about the character having similar reactions in a similar environment to what we’ve already seen (tells us what we already know).</p>

<p>The Exercise:
Select a scene from one of your works in progress and determine as to whether or not you can answer all of the prompts below. If you can’t, use the information you gain by answering the prompts to attempt to create more illustrative scenes.</p>

<p>Interior/Exterior:<br />
Location:<br />
Day/Time:<br />
What is happening?<br />
What is the main source of conflict?<br />
What are the characters’ agenda?<br />
What is the emotional arc of the scene?<br />
Where does the emotion start?<br />
Where does the emotion finish?<br />
Are you showing the reader what’s going on or are you telling the reader what’s going on?</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="Exercise" /><category term="Exercise" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I break down the key differences between illustrative and non-illustrative scenes in writing. Strong scenes actively challenge characters and show them making decisions in varied environments, revealing growth through their changing responses to similar situations. To help writers create more dynamic scenes, I've developed a checklist of essential elements - from setting and timing to emotional arcs and conflict sources. This framework helps identify whether you're truly showing character development or merely telling readers what to think.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beat of the Day - You’re a Capricious Raconteur</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/11/15/BotD-You're-a-Capricious-Raconteur/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beat of the Day - You’re a Capricious Raconteur" /><published>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/11/15/BotD-You're-a-Capricious-Raconteur</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/11/15/BotD-You're-a-Capricious-Raconteur/"><![CDATA[<p>This is a storyteller (an unreliable narrator) who withholds information, lies to, or misleads the reader, casting doubt on the narrative. You can use this device to engage readers on a deeper level, forcing them to come to their own conclusions when the narrator’s point of view can’t be trusted. There are many ways to create a story with an unreliable narrator. Your narrator could have biases, and want to steer readers towards believing the same thing they do. Your narrator could experience hallucinations or delusions that make it difficult for them to understand objective reality. Your narrator could be deceptive and tell lies or be untrue to themself. Your narrator could be a child who doesn’t fully understand the complex workings of society within the context of your story. However you choose to make your narrator unreliable, you need to find a way of making readers question the narrator’s credibility. Does the narrator’s unreliability become more obvious over time, or was it always obvious that they are not to be trusted? Is there a plot twist at the end that reveals that they’re unreliable? An unreliable narrator can vastly alter the tone of a story. Consider what you’ve written. How would this story be different with an objective or omniscient perspective? How can this technique be useful in adding depth to a story?</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="BotD" /><category term="BotD" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I explore how unreliable narrators can add complexity and intrigue to storytelling by deliberately misleading or withholding information from readers. Whether through personal bias, mental instability, deception, or limited understanding, these narrators force readers to question the narrative's credibility and draw their own conclusions. I examine how this technique fundamentally alters a story's tone compared to using objective or omniscient perspectives, creating deeper engagement through uncertainty.]]></summary></entry></feed>