<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-01T10:47:14-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Heist Outline - The Perfect Score</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/31/A-Heist-Outline-The-Perfect-Score/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Heist Outline - The Perfect Score" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/31/A-Heist-Outline-The-Perfect-Score</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/31/A-Heist-Outline-The-Perfect-Score/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="newly-released-shadows">Newly Released Shadows:</h3>
<p>This is where you’re going to introduce the protagonist, a highly skilled thief, who has recently been released from a large stint in federal prison.</p>

<h3 id="a-desperate-gambit">A Desperate Gambit:</h3>
<p>Newly released from federal prison, the protagonist is desperately in need of money and in order to get a large amount of money quickly, they decide to conduct a high-stakes heist.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Newly Released Shadows: This is where you’re going to introduce the protagonist, a highly skilled thief, who has recently been released from a large stint in federal prison.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Move Ahead Three Spaces - An Exercise</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/exercise/2024/10/31/Move-Ahead-Three-Spaces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Move Ahead Three Spaces - An Exercise" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/exercise/2024/10/31/Move-Ahead-Three-Spaces</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/exercise/2024/10/31/Move-Ahead-Three-Spaces/"><![CDATA[<p>Advancing the narrative by jumping forward in time provides a unique opportunity to reposition your characters within the overarching story, offering a chance to showcase the consequences of their actions. It’s akin to the closing of a curtain between acts in a theatrical performance, allowing for a shift in narrative styles, settings, and the progression of seasons.</p>

<p>The beauty of this narrative technique lies in the reader’s ability to intuitively bridge the temporal gaps, especially when overarching patterns remain discernible. Readers, familiar with the rhythms of life, education, or work, can easily infer what transpires in the unchronicled weeks or months. For instance, in a magical school like Hogwarts, we don’t need to witness every weekly class or mundane occurrence because we possess a collective understanding of how educational institutions operate.</p>

<p>However, it’s important to note that the decision to skip scenes should never be arbitrary. If doing so has little discernible impact on the story’s development, it serves as a clear indicator that those scenes might be superfluous and better left on the cutting room floor.</p>

<p>To further streamline your narrative, consider amalgamating scenes and settings where applicable. For instance, if your character needs to engage in a heated argument before embarking on a hiking adventure, merge these elements. The argument can unfold against the backdrop of a challenging trail, lending depth to the characters’ emotional journey and minimizing unnecessary scene transitions.</p>

<p>Incorporate thoughtful transitions into your storytelling. These serve as a compass guiding readers through the temporal jumps. Whether it’s a subtle change in the weather, a shift in the characters’ appearance, or a brief reflection on the passage of time, such cues help create a seamless narrative flow, ensuring that readers never feel disoriented when navigating through the story’s temporal landscape.</p>

<p>In conclusion, the art of skipping forward in time within a narrative should be wielded with precision and purpose. It provides an effective tool for managing pacing, maintaining reader engagement, and emphasizing the critical elements of your story while allowing for a dynamic and immersive storytelling experience.</p>

<p>The Exercise:
Consider the Following:
Consequences of Skipping: How will skipping ahead in time impact your characters? What important developments, changes, or growth might occur during this skipped period?</p>

<p>Character Reflection: What significant events or moments might your characters reflect on when they resume the story after the time skip? How have these moments shaped them or their relationships?</p>

<p>Transitions: What transitional elements or cues will you use to smoothly guide readers through the skipped time? Think about how you can create a seamless transition so that readers can intuitively grasp the changes that have occurred.</p>

<p>Maintaining Suspense: Are there unresolved questions or plot points left hanging before the time skip? How will you maintain suspense and keep readers engaged even as you jump forward in time?</p>

<p>Character Arcs: Explore how the skipped time impacts the character arcs. What internal changes or growth might occur during this period? How will it affect their goals and motivations?</p>

<p>Foreshadowing: Think about how events or developments during the skipped time can foreshadow future plot twists or conflicts. This can add depth and anticipation to the story.</p>

<p>Reader Engagement: Consider how to keep readers engaged during the skipped time. Are there unresolved subplots or mysteries that can be introduced before the skip to maintain intrigue?</p>

<p>Parallel Storylines: Explore the possibility of parallel storylines. While skipping time for one set of characters, you could delve into the experiences of other characters during that period, providing a different perspective on the narrative.</p>

<p>Emotional Impact: Reflect on the emotional impact of the time skip on both characters and readers. What emotions are at play during the skipped time? How can you convey them effectively?</p>

<p>Now, list three events the reader might anticipate will happen in your story, such as a regional competition, prom or a wedding. Could you feasibly skip ahead to one of them?</p>

<p>What are your thoughts on this exercise? Drop me a comment below!</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="exercise" /><category term="writing" /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Advancing the narrative by jumping forward in time provides a unique opportunity to reposition your characters within the overarching story, offering a chance to showcase the consequences of their actions. It’s akin to the closing of a curtain between acts in a theatrical performance, allowing for a shift in narrative styles, settings, and the progression of seasons.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FtBotB - A Zombie Tale</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/ftbotb/2024/10/31/FtBotB-The-Price-of-War/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FtBotB - A Zombie Tale" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/ftbotb/2024/10/31/FtBotB-The-Price-of-War</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/ftbotb/2024/10/31/FtBotB-The-Price-of-War/"><![CDATA[<div>


<div class="container" style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <a href="/assets/images/cwzomb.png" data-toggle="lightbox" data-title="">
        <img class="container post-image" alt="" src="/assets/images/cwzomb.png" />

    </a>
    <div class="container figure-caption" style="margin-top: -16px !important; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 16px">
        
    </div>
</div>

</div>

<h2 id="from-the-back-of-the-book">From the Back of the Book:</h2>
<h2 id="working-title">Working Title:</h2>
<p>The Price of War
 </p>
<h2 id="story-synopsis">Story Synopsis:</h2>
<p>The story opens in the midst of The American Civil War. A young confederate soldier stumbles upon an ancient Aniyvwiyan artifact deep within a hidden cave system. The artifact possesses mysterious powers that could potentially alter the course of the war. The soldier becomes entranced by the artifact’s allure, hearing whispers of promised power and victory. Tempted by its influence, he decides to present the artifact to his commanding officers, believing it could turn the tide of the war in the confederacy’s favor. Confederate leaders, desperate for any advantage, begin to delve into the artifact’s origins and its potential use. They kidnap a Aniyvwiya Adawehi, who they then force to uncover dark rituals and incantations that can harness its power. However, these new insights and the new power comes at a terrible cost. Sinister experiments and sacrifices are conducted in secret, turning the war into a battle not just of armies, but of ancient Aniyvwiyan magic. Union spies eventually catch wind of the confederacy’s newfound power and the existence of the artifact. They report back to their leaders, who are both skeptical and alarmed by the potential threat. A special task force is assembled to investigate and counter the confederate’s supernatural advantage. As the war progresses, the use of the artifact’s power becomes more apparent. Battlefields are transformed into nightmarish landscapes, with the dead rising, as grotesque and unholy abominations. Soldiers on both sides are forced to confront not only their mortal enemies, but also the dead horrors unleashed by the power of the artifact. The confederate soldier, who initially discovered the artifact begins to question the cost of wielding such power. He witnesses the toll it takes on his fellow soldiers and the land itself. Haunted by the horrors he has unleashed, he starts to doubt the righteousness of their cause. A union soldier, tasked with infiltrating the confederate ranks in order to learn more about the power and the artifact, finds himself forming an unexpected bond with the conflicted confederate soldier. Together, they free the Aniyvwiyan Adawehi, in the hopes of uncovering the true nature of the artifact, the ancient evil it contains and a way to contain it. The Aniyvwiyan Adawehi reveals that the artifact is merely a vessel for a malevolent entity from an ancient Aniyvwiyan legend. This entity has been manipulating both sides, feeding on the chaos and bloodshed of the war. Its ultimate goal is to resurrect an ancient army and claim dominion over the land. The union and confederate soldiers, now united by a common cause, race against time to find a way to seal the artifact’s power and banish the entity back to its realm. They seek the help from other tribes who hold the knowledge of ancient rituals and countermeasures. In a climactic battle, the combined forces of union and confederate soldiers, along with their tribal allies, make a final stand against the entity and its horrendous resurrected army. The fate of the nation hangs in the balance as they fight not only for victory, but for the very soul of America. Though the entity is ultimately defeated, and the artifact sealed away, the cost is high. All three sides have suffered immense losses, and the nation is left scarred by the horrors they’ve both experienced and witnessed. The war ends, with no clear victor. The wounds run deep, and the memory of the supernatural conflict lingers. In the aftermath of the war, the survivors attempt to rebuild their lives and the nation. However, the scars of the supernatural battles remain, and strange occurrences continue to haunt the land. Some fear that the entity’s influence is not entirely vanquished, leaving an uneasy peace in its wake. The end of the story explores themes of sacrifice, the power of unity in the face of adversity, and the consequences of wielding power without fully understanding its true nature. It delves into the complexities of war, the blurring of moral lines, and the enduring impact of the choices made during the conflict.
 </p>
<h2 id="questions">Questions:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Would you purchase and read this novel if you saw it in a bookstore?</li>
  <li>Would you read this novel if it were given to you as a gift?</li>
  <li>How do you feel after having read the synopsis?</li>
  <li>What is your overall opinion of the genre?</li>
  <li>Have you ever read a alternate history, a zombie or a combination of the two novel before?
 </li>
</ol>

<p>Drop me a comment down below. I’d love to hear your thoughts.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="FtBotB" /><category term="writing" /><category term="FtBotB" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Alternate History Outline - Not Your Great-Great Grandfather’s Civil War</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/31/An-Alternate-History-Outline/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Alternate History Outline - Not Your Great-Great Grandfather’s Civil War" /><published>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/31/An-Alternate-History-Outline</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/31/An-Alternate-History-Outline/"><![CDATA[<p>With the “An Alternate History Outline - Not Your Great-Great Grandfather’s Civil War” outline, you’ll gain the opportunity to write a story that will explore a richly imagined alternate history filled with divergent events, unique challenges, and the profound impact of choices made in an altered historical context.</p>

<p>Granted, this is simply an example outline. Note, that your alternate history story need not include the elements concerning The Civil War adventure, a romance and a grief arc, as I’ve included here. Your alternate history story may look entirely different from what I’ve outlined here, and that’s okay, as I simply provided this outline in order to give you an idea of what an alternate history story might look like.</p>

<p>Note: This is a rare one, in that I’ve created a three-in-one outline with this one. It contains an alternate history outline, a romance outline and a grief outline.</p>

<p>Now, without further ado, let’s dive in.</p>

<h2 id="an-alternate-history-outline---not-your-great-great-grandfathers-civil-war">An Alternate History Outline - Not Your Great-Great Grandfather’s Civil War:</h2>
<h3 id="a-war-torn-prelude">A War-Torn Prelude:</h3>
<p>Paint a vivid picture of the divided America during the Civil War era. Highlight the deep-rooted tensions and suffering caused by the war, as well as the suffering experienced by the soldiers, civilians and slaves on both sides and emphasize the urgency of the situation.</p>

<h3 id="sorcerys-subtle-shift">Sorcery’s Subtle Shift:</h3>
<p>Explore a “what if” scenario, the divergence point where history takes an alternate path. What if a secret society of magicians wields a secret, yet significant influence over The American Civil War? This is the core premise of the story, steering it in unexpected directions.</p>

<h3 id="a-clandestine-cabal">A Clandestine Cabal:</h3>
<p>Detail the existence of the secret magical society. Explain how it’s comprised of individuals from both the North and South, who share a common goal, that is to harness the magical energy generated by the war for their own, as of now, hidden agendas.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---a-romantic-opening">A Romance - A Romantic Opening:</h3>
<p>This is where the protagonist and the love interest are shown doing their own thing. This should not be confused with the meet cute. They may be shown in the same place, doing the same things, but they don’t know each other yet and they haven’t met yet either.</p>

<h3 id="an-inward-tempest">An Inward Tempest:</h3>
<p>Dive into the protagonist’s internal conflict as they somehow become acutely aware of the magical society’s secret significant influence, thus causing them to experience a moral dilemma and emotional turmoil regarding the sudden discovery. Dive into the internal conflict experienced by the protagonist. Explore their moral dilemma and emotional struggle, torn between loyalty to the society, that before now, they viewed as benevolent, and a desire for peace.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---a-wartime-meet-cute">A Romance - A Wartime Meet Cute:</h3>
<p>This is where the protagonist and the love interest meet or are brought together on the page at the same time to set off the story. In a rom com, a meet cute sometimes involves humor or a screwball situation, but it doesn’t have to be that. It could be intense or scary. This meeting is the event that sets our characters off in the direction of falling in love, even if they hate each other at this point. If the characters already know each other, there is something different in this meeting than in all their previous meetings.</p>

<h3 id="a-secret-rendezvous-with-a-rebel-mage">A Secret Rendezvous with a Rebel Mage:</h3>
<p>Introduce a charismatic Southern mage (Northern aligned) who mysteriously arrived from the future, who becomes an unexpected ally to the protagonist. A mage who is morally dedicated to ending the war, stopping the malevolent mages from seizing power, and bringing about peace through good, natural magic. Highlight their charisma and conviction towards their mission.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---a-magical-resistance">A Romance - A Magical Resistance:</h3>
<p>The first response to the meet cute is nearly always resistance or a butting of heads between the love interest. “The idea of a fake engagement is a terrible idea.” or “We can’t be in the same room together. How will we be able to share the only car left to rent to get to the conference?” However, the resistance isn’t always from dislike. In a friends-to-lovers situation, often the resistance is trying to avoid revealing their true feelings. Sometimes, the meet-cute is friendly and there is an attraction between the lovebirds, yet there is still resistance. This response is rooted in their goals and/or inner conflicts. Sometimes there is an attempt to avoid each other which brings us to the next beat.</p>

<h3 id="the-enchanted-underground">The Enchanted Underground:</h3>
<p>Explain how the protagonist and the Southern mage collaborate with other like-minded individuals in order to create a magical version of the Underground Railroad and describe the spells and magical abilities they employ to aid all of the runaway slaves and all of the formerly Southern aligned soldiers in their bid for freedom.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---amidst-the-war-were-stuck-together">A Romance - Amidst the War, We’re Stuck Together:</h3>
<p>Right now, the protagonist and the love interest are without a choice or reluctantly agreeing to a situation that puts them together. Snow storms and stuck elevators would be a situation in which they’re stuck without a choice. Working in the same company or living in the same building would also fit this. A fake relationship or temporary partnership would involve a reluctant agreement. This beat is important because our lovebirds need to be together in order to fall in love.</p>

<h3 id="gettysburgs-mystical-turn">Gettysburg’s Mystical Turn:</h3>
<p>Provide vivid details of the magical intervention at the Battle of Gettysburg. Describe the protagonist’s, the Southern Mage’s and other allies’ use of magic to change the course of the battle, hastening the Union’s victory, thereby accelerating the end of the war.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---were-fighting-the-war-and-the-attraction">A Romance - We’re Fighting the War and the Attraction:</h3>
<p>The protagonist and the love interest enter this phase fully intending to keep their walls up. They’re focused on their goals and not letting the other person get in their way. If they don’t get along, there is usually banter and arguing. If they do get along, there is usually inner dialogue about how they can’t fall for the other.</p>

<h3 id="the-secret-societys-sinister-schemes">The Secret Society’s Sinister Schemes:</h3>
<p>Highlight the escalating tensions between the protagonist and the magical society, as the leaders help the Southern line intensify their efforts to prolong the war. Meanwhile, the leaders begin to perceive the protagonist and the Southern Mage as a threat to their ultimate goal.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-waning-resistance">A Romance - The Waning Resistance:</h3>
<p>As the protagonist and the love interest spend time together, their initial impressions start to change. This is especially true in an enemies-to-lovers story. But even when they get along (friends to lovers), time together shifts their feelings or heightens them (in the case of unrequited love). In this section, they begin to entertain the possibility of a relationship, physically and/or emotionally. Note that kissing and even sex may have already occurred (in the case of a non-sweet book), but this is where the wall of resistance wanes.</p>

<h3 id="antietams-altered-agenda">Antietam’s Altered Agenda:</h3>
<p>Detail the protagonist and the Southern mage’s attempt to prevent the devastatingly bloody Battle of Antietam, by revealing the magical society’s involvement to to both the Union and Confederacy, leading to a potential cease-fire.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---a-shared-desire">A Romance - A Shared Desire:</h3>
<p>Resistance is futile as desire leads the protagonist and the love interest to consider giving into a relationship. Note this doesn’t have to be sensual desire. In sweet romance, this is simply moving away from resistance towards considering a relationship.</p>

<h3 id="a-fathers-dark-betrayal">A Father’s Dark Betrayal:</h3>
<p>Explore the moment of betrayal when the father of the protagonist secretly aligns himself with those within the magical society whose goals are aligned with the South, after losing the war, we’re hoping to restart hostilities, leading to the protagonist’s capture and leaving the Southern mage assumed dead. This throws the protagonist into a harrowing, life altering ordeal that accompanies severe consequences and life-altering personal sacrifices.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---the-precipice">The Mourning Path - The Precipice:</h3>
<p>The precipice is where you’re standing as you learn about the death of someone dear to you. It is a place filled with so many different emotions that you hardly know who you are, much less begin to process them.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-ut-oh-moment">A Romance - The Ut-Oh Moment:</h3>
<p>I don’t know where the term pinch point came from, but I much prefer Ut-Oh. This is a situation in which an antagonist or conflict appears to remind the protagonist and the love interest what’s at stake. This first one should be on the smaller side. It’s like a tap on the shoulder reminding one (or they both can have an ut-oh) what can happen.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---losshurt">The Mourning Path - Loss/Hurt:</h3>
<p>Whether it’s a close friend, spouse, partner, parent, child, or other relative, the pain one feels immediately after the death of a loved one can feel overwhelming. You may experience waves of intense and very difficult emotions, ranging from profound sadness, emptiness, and despair to shock and numbness.</p>

<h3 id="a-gift-from-the-magi">A Gift From the Magi:</h3>
<p>Explain how the protagonist escapes with the aid of the still alive Southern mage, both embarking on a journey of redemption and self-discovery as they seek to make amends for their previous actions and find a powerful enchantment that the Southern mage claims will change everything.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---shock">The Mourning Path - Shock:</h3>
<p>Shock is typically experienced as one of the first stages in the grief process, and eventually it wears off. For some, shock recedes very quickly. For others, shock lasts for hours or days. Everyone is different and there is no right or wrong way to experience shock.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---imagining-the-happily-ever-after">A Romance - Imagining the Happily Ever After:</h3>
<p>Despite the ut-oh, the protagonist and the love interest are drawing ever closer. They’re rethinking goals and concerns. They believe they can overcome the conflicts, but selfishly. They want their cake and to eat it too, but they haven’t grown enough yet, so they’re susceptible to their inner demons (conflict) and the antagonist and their minions.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---numbness">The Mourning Path - Numbness:</h3>
<p>Some of us feel sad when someone dies. Some of us feel angry. But some of us feel nothing at all. Emotional numbness can be linked with a type of grief called ‘inhibited grief,’ which is characterized by suppressed emotions.</p>

<h3 id="president-lincolns-mystic-shield">President Lincoln’s Mystic Shield:</h3>
<p>Describe the use of the newly acquired powerful enchantment to save President Abraham Lincoln from being assassinated by John Wilkes Booth. Highlight the significance of this act, as it alters the course of history once again, underscoring the significance of the protagonist and the Southern Mage’s original mission.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---denial">The Mourning Path - Denial:</h3>
<p>Denial is the refusal to accept the facts of the loss, either consciously or unconsciously. If dealing with death is personal, there is a refusal to take necessary steps to prepare for death, such as a will.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-happily-ever-after-is-within-reach">A Romance - The Happily Ever After is Within Reach:</h3>
<p>This is the famous honeymoon moment, but alas, the protagonist and the love interest still haven’t dealt with the tension and the conflicts that avidly threaten their burgeoning love.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---emotional-outbursts">The Mourning Path - Emotional Outbursts:</h3>
<p>You’re definitely upset, but more often than not, you’re not upset at who you think you’re upset at. Grief and emotional outbursts tend to walk hand in hand.</p>

<h3 id="a-sorcerous-showdown">A Sorcerous Showdown:</h3>
<p>Create a dramatic climax with the epic showdown between the protagonist, the Southern Mage, and the Southern aligned leaders of the magical society, featuring intense magical battles, dramatic ideological conflicts and the ultimate triumph of the protagonist and the Southern Mage.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---anger">The Mourning Path - Anger:</h3>
<p>Many people do in fact feel angry when someone we love dies. Angry at being abandoned, angry at the extent of the pain, angry that our life is changed, angry that managing grief feels difficult, and angry that the world suddenly feels different—empty, unsafe, or lonely. Swallowed feelings don’t disappear.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---doubts-and-fears">A Romance - Doubts and Fears:</h3>
<p>Personal fears and conflicts are creating doubt in the protagonist and love interest’s feelings for one another. Fears and inner conflicts cause the protagonist and the love interest to slow things down.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---fear">The Mourning Path - Fear:</h3>
<p>If you search fear symptoms on the internet, you get a list of very similar feelings in both grief and fear. Grief feels like fear because it leaves you reeling in uncertainty. If you think about it, most of the things that we think give us a sense of certainty in our lives, do not. We assume that if we live right, eat right, take care of ourselves, and are loving and thoughtful, we will be rewarded and those we love will be kept safe. When the worst happens, we then question who we are, and where is God? What do I do? Where do I turn next? How do I move forward? Do I even want to move at all? Nothing makes sense and caring about anything seems fruitless. We don’t feel safe in our own skin. And we don’t know whom we can trust.</p>

<h3 id="unveiling-the-arcane-veneer">Unveiling the Arcane Veneer:</h3>
<p>Reveal the true nature and history of the entirety of the magical society, and how their power is finally broken, shedding light on their true motivations and the depths of their former influence.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---searching">The Mourning Path - Searching:</h3>
<p>It’s hard to explain this “searching” to people who haven’t experienced it because it isn’t just a matter of looking around for the person and finding they’re not there. Instead, searching, in this context, means doing all sorts of things to try and repair the physical attachment - like seeking out sights, sounds, smells, people, and places that remind you of the person. Sometimes you get so close that for a split second, you honestly think you’ve managed to cross the void. But then, once again, your loved one is gone. It’s like they’ve picked up the phone, said “hello”, and the signal cuts out.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---ut-oh-part-deux">A Romance - Ut-Oh Part Deux:</h3>
<p>This ut-oh is a bigger one than the last. It’s a whack on the head, reminding the protagonist and the love interest of everything they could lose by abandoning their goal. For example, a CEO falling for his admin might get a talking to from a board member about the possibility of being forced out for having a relationship with an insubordinate and putting the company at risk for a lawsuit. The first ut-oh caused hesitation, but this one makes them stop in their tracks and rethink the situation, and what they’re willing to risk. Remember, they haven’t grown so, their thinking tends to be based in their fears.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---disorganization">The Mourning Path - Disorganization:</h3>
<p>Just from a superficial point of view, the face of a grieving person can be pretty damn messy – bloodshot eyes, runny, red nose, puffy eyelids, red nose and other outward appearances that we might want to hide. Grief can also throw other physical aspects out of whack. An example: The house is in complete disarray.</p>

<h3 id="the-slow-reconstruction-of-hope">The Slow Reconstruction of Hope:</h3>
<p>Explore the aftermath of the magical society’s ultimate defeat, the conclusion of the war and the efforts made to slowly begin to rebuild a war-torn nation, with the protagonist and the Southern Mage playing vital roles in aiding the post-war reconstruction.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---panic">The Mourning Path - Panic:</h3>
<p>Grief can make us feel like we’ve lost our sense of safety and control. It’s natural to feel panic or worried about what might happen next or even to worry that we might lose someone else in the future.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-retreat">A Romance - The Retreat:</h3>
<p>After the big ut-oh, the protagonist, the love interest or perhaps both pulls away. They don’t want to risk their heart and their goal, and they decide to choose the goal instead. The other character may notice this distance and pull away as well.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---the-valley">The Mourning Path - The Valley:</h3>
<p>The valley is where you’re sitting when you’re neck deep in the grief after losing someone dear to you. You can’t see a way out of it, and in most cases you have no interest in leaving in the first place.</p>

<h3 id="americas-altered-aura">America’s Altered Aura:</h3>
<p>Paint a compelling picture of a transformed America following The Civil War, shaped not only by historical events, too by highlighting the societal, political, and cultural changes brought about by the actions of the protagonist, the Southern Mage, their allies and the presence of good magic.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---loneliness">The Mourning Path - Loneliness:</h3>
<p>Loneliness is a natural part of grief, and it is one of the more trying aspects of accepting a loss. When a loved one dies, a hole is left that no one and nothing else can fill. It is as if no one else can know or understand. The intense and mixed feelings of grief can lead to separation and isolation from others.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-black-moment">A Romance - The Black Moment:</h3>
<p>This is where the shit hits the fan for the protagonist and the love interest. Everything that could go wrong, does go wrong. Done well, your readers are weeping or worried (in the case of a suspense). If motivations aren’t strong or if the stakes are weak, a black moment can feel predicable or worse, it can annoy readers. The black moment must feel believable and make sense. Something as little as a miscommunication isn’t enough for a black moment. This moment needs to feel like the end of the road for our budding couple.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---guilt">The Mourning Path - Guilt:</h3>
<p>Guilt can be a common yet complex emotion in grief. The truth is that we can feel guilty about so many things. Guilt does not always have to be rational to be real. That means even when we realize our guilt is not based on reality, we still may experience it.</p>

<h3 id="the-price-of-magical-penance">The Price of Magical Penance:</h3>
<p>Delve into the personal sacrifices made by key individuals throughout the protagonist and the Southern Mage’s journey for peace and justice, exploring the emotional toll of their choices on their lives and relationships. Delve into the personal sacrifices made by the protagonist and the Southern mage throughout their journey and explore the emotional toll of their choices, as well.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---isolation">The Mourning Path - Isolation:</h3>
<p>Experiencing grief can be an isolating experience for many people. The only person who can truly understand your loss is you; nobody else knew your loved one in the same way you did, and no one knew them in the exact way you did.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---permeated-in-misery">A Romance - Permeated In Misery:</h3>
<p>This is the aftermath of the black moment. Initially, the protagonist, the love interest or perhaps both, convinced they’re right, go off in an attempt to regain their past normal life.  The problem is that they can’t go back. The more they try, the more miserable they feel. They should live in this moment a little bit. Too often, writers rush to relieve the agony of the black moment, but you should bring home how much they’ve lost by not choosing to change, by not choosing love. I want to point out here that characters don’t have to give up their goal for love.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---depression">The Mourning Path - Depression:</h3>
<p>The depression associated with grief is like being in an ongoing, heightened state of mourning that keeps you from healing. Signs and symptoms of complicated grief may include: Intense sorrow, pain and rumination over the loss of your loved one. Focus on little else but your loved one’s death. Extreme focus on reminders of the loved one or excessive avoidance of reminders. Intense and persistent longing or pining for the deceased. Problems accepting the death. Numbness or detachment. Bitterness about your loss. Feeling that life holds no meaning or purpose. Lack of trust in others. Inability to enjoy life or think back on positive experiences with your loved one. Complicated grief also may be indicated if you continue to: Have trouble carrying out normal routines. Isolate from others and withdraw from social activities. Experience depression, deep sadness, guilt or self-blame. Believe that you did something wrong or could have prevented the death. Feel life isn’t worth living without your loved one. Wish you had died along with your loved one.</p>

<h3 id="a-legacy-in-flux">A Legacy in Flux:</h3>
<p>Examine the enduring effects of the actions of the protagonist, the Southern mage and their allies on future generations and explore the nation’s new historical narrative, with the protagonist, the Southern Mage and their allies’ intertwined relationships and stories becoming an integral part of the broader historical tapestry.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---the-hard-climb-out">The Mourning Path - The Hard Climb Out:</h3>
<p>The hard climb out is when you start to look past the grief that has all but consumed you and you start to look at what life means and what life looks like beyond that grief.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-ah-ha-moment">A Romance - The Ah-Ha Moment:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist, the love interest or perhaps both realize their fears and inner conflicts getting in their way, and accept that they love the other person. This is where the real growth takes place. In order for the past problems (conflicts and ut-ohs) not to cause problems in the future, the protagonist and the love interest need to grow into new people.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---loss-adjustment">The Mourning Path - Loss Adjustment:</h3>
<p>You know that you’ve reached this stage when you can do the following: Recognize the loss. React to the separation. Recollect and re-experience. Relinquish old attachments. Readjust and reinvest in life.</p>

<h3 id="dawn-of-a-new-era">Dawn of a New Era:</h3>
<p>Begin the conclusion of the story with a vision of a united, transformed America after the war and new revelations about the magical society.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---recovery-guilt">The Mourning Path - Recovery Guilt:</h3>
<p>In recovery guilt, grievers tend to look at other people who have been grieving a similar loss or perhaps even the same loss, and sense that they are coping too well.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---the-grand-gesture">A Romance - The Grand Gesture:</h3>
<p>This is when either the protagonist or the love interest reaches out, putting all on the line for the other person. It’s different from earlier attempts that played it safe. Here, they’re vulnerable.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---re-entry-troubles">The Mourning Path - Re-Entry Troubles:</h3>
<p>Once the effort is made to get back into the normal routine, the pain of loss makes it difficult to be as trusting and open as before the loss. Suspicion must be battled constantly. Friends and families are tested again and again.</p>

<h3 id="a-magical-america">A Magical America:</h3>
<p>Detail how the presence of good magic continues to shape the nation’s destiny in the years following the Civil War. Describe the emergence of new mages, practices and magical institutions.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---new-relationships">The Mourning Path - New Relationships:</h3>
<p>It’s not always easy to understand that it is possible to love and miss someone, while having room to be happy and involved with new people and new relationships.</p>

<h3 id="a-romance---happily-ever-after">A Romance - Happily Ever After:</h3>
<p>The happily ever after scene is when the the protagonist or the love interest is also vulnerable and they come together with new understanding and a commitment to each other.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---new-patterns">The Mourning Path - New Patterns:</h3>
<p>Most of our habituated behavior serves us well. Checking for traffic, when crossing a street, keeps us safe. Brushing our teeth and washing our hands promotes better health. The list is endless. Once that belief system and our habits are established, we follow them without a second thought. The fact is that these habits become such an integral part of who we are, that anything that doesn’t fall within them tends to receive an automatic critical response from us. This is all about changing old habits on how to deal with emotionally painful events and creating new ones that help you move through and beyond them. It’s about helping you discover those things that are incomplete in relationships and finding a way to let go of those painful feelings that you have stuffed inside. It’s not about forgetting the past, but rather being able to effectively deal with it.</p>

<h3 id="global-ripples-of-enchantment">Global Ripples of Enchantment:</h3>
<p>Hint at the international repercussions of this new, magical America, suggesting that the impact extends well beyond its borders and now influences global events.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---hope">The Mourning Path - Hope:</h3>
<p>Gradually, the pain subsides and the world becomes bearable again. Hope sneaks through the cracks in the walls built up as protection against hurt. Energy is regained. The process of rebuilding seems possible.</p>

<h3 id="achieving-an-ethical-arcane-balance">Achieving an Ethical Arcane Balance:</h3>
<p>Raise thought-provoking questions about the ethical use of magic in a post-war world, exploring all of the challenges, dilemmas and unintended consequences faced as individuals seek to maintain a delicate balance.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---affirmations">The Mourning Path - Affirmations:</h3>
<p>The loss is accepted without bitterness. Death begins to give way to new life. Purpose is regained. A new, different reality is where life is to be lived.</p>

<h3 id="uncharted-mystical-realms">Uncharted Mystical Realms:</h3>
<p>Mention some of the lingering, unsolved magical mysteries, thus preserving the enigmatic nature of the magical world.</p>

<h3 id="the-mourning-path---helping-others">The Mourning Path - Helping Others:</h3>
<p>When someone in your life is dealing with a loss, you now intrinsically understand just what to expect as they go through the grieving process and you can help them get through it.</p>

<h3 id="reflecting-on-magical-history">Reflecting on Magical History:</h3>
<p>Contemplate broader themes of power, responsibility, and the role of individuals in shaping history, offering insights into the complex interplay of magic and humanity.</p>

<h3 id="new-magical-enigmatic-horizons">New Magical, Enigmatic Horizons:</h3>
<p>Finally, end with some surprising revelations or hints at new magical adventures, leaving a sense of wonder and curiosity about what the future holds for the protagonist, the Southern mage and this new magical America, leaving the door unlocked for new adventures.</p>

<p>How do you feel about this crazy outline? Would you use it or use something similar to it? Drop me a comment down below. I’d love to hear your thoughts.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the “An Alternate History Outline - Not Your Great-Great Grandfather’s Civil War” outline, you’ll gain the opportunity to write a story that will explore a richly imagined alternate history filled with divergent events, unique challenges, and the profound impact of choices made in an altered historical context.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Hero’s Journey Via the Zodiac</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/30/The-Hero's-Journey-By-the-Zodiac/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Hero’s Journey Via the Zodiac" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/30/The-Hero's-Journey-By-the-Zodiac</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/30/The-Hero's-Journey-By-the-Zodiac/"><![CDATA[<div>


<div class="container" style="display: inline; align-content: center">
    <a href="/assets/images/zod.jpg" data-toggle="lightbox" data-title="Outline Picture">
        <img class="container post-image-small" alt="Outline Picture" src="/assets/images/zod.jpg" />

    </a>
    
         
        
    
</div>

</div>

<h3 id="aries---the-call-to-adventure">Aries - The Call to Adventure:</h3>
<p>The myth of the Golden Fleece sets the stage for the original conflict behind the whole adventure. An angry cloud nymph who’s husband king left her for another woman creates a drought. The new wife plots to have the king’s children sacrificed to save the town’s crops, and the cloud mother sweeps in with a flying ram to save her children. The ram is then sacrificed and its fleece hung on an oak tree sacred to Mars, the warrior god who creates conditions that allow crops to grow.</p>

<p>The call to adventure comes when the old concepts, ideals, and emotional patterns no longer fit, says Campbell. The herald calling to destiny is often dark and judged evil: with Phrixus it’s the stepmother, and later it’s Pelias, sending Jason and the Argonauts on their quest.</p>

<h3 id="taurus---the-refusal-of-the-call">Taurus - The Refusal of the Call:</h3>
<p>Venus, ruling Taurus in her earthly aspect, can “give military victory, sexual success, good fortune and prosperity,” making life indeed so comfortable the hero might just refuse the call and dismiss the adventure.</p>

<p>Refusing the call converts the adventure into its negative, says Campbell, eventually turning the flowering world of the hero into a wasteland even if, like King Minos, he succeeds in building a great empire. For the king’s greed turns all that fertile energy inward, which results in a walled labyrinth hiding a monstrous creature: the Minotaur. Thankfully, Theseus comes and kills the monster, and so the adventure continues.</p>

<h3 id="gemini---some-supernatural-aid">Gemini - Some Supernatural Aid:</h3>
<p>Every quest comes with some form of help or guidance: the hero meets a mentor, receiving what Campbell calls supernatural aid. This represents some protecting power of destiny, or helpful forces from the unconscious, which appear once the hero is committed to the quest.</p>

<p>This stage happens under the ruler ship of Mercury, messenger of the gods and guide of souls to the underworld. In the myth of the twins Castor and Pollux, regarded as helpers of mankind, one twin is immortal, the other is not. When Castor dies, Pollux strikes a deal with Zeus so that he can share his immortality with Castor. By accepting to be mortal, Pollux makes a real commitment to the adventure of life.</p>

<h3 id="cancer---crossing-the-threshold">Cancer - Crossing the Threshold:</h3>
<p>With the help of supernatural forces, the hero is ready to leave the limits of the ordinary world and cross the first threshold. This stage occurs under the rulership of the moon and its instinctive need for home and security.</p>

<p>Heracles fights the multi-headed monster Hydra, living at the entrance of the underworld and acting as a threshold guardian. Sensing that Heracles is winning, the goddess Hera sends the giant crab Karkinos to distract him but the hero crushes it under his foot. Thus he emerges from the crab’s regressive pull in a kind of rebirth, similar to what Campbell calls the belly of the whale, a final separation from the hero’s known self and world.</p>

<h3 id="leo---the-road-of-trials">Leo - The Road of Trials:</h3>
<p>Now moving into the unknown, the hero embarks on the road of trials where he must face a series of tests to begin the transformation (often in patterns of threes).</p>

<p>Under the ruler ship of the Sun – associated with the conscious ego, personal power, creativity and leadership – Heracles prepares to fight the Nemean Lion. The challenge lasts thirty days, during which he first tries to kill the lion with normal weapons and fails, then with a clever use of darkness (or supernatural aid), he knocks out the lion and strangles it with his bare hands. Failing at skinning the lion with his knife, he again receives supernatural help, with Athena telling him to use one of the lion’s claws. Finally, Hercules wears the lion’s skin, and in this way symbolizes the transformation.</p>

<h3 id="virgo---the-meeting-with-the-goddess">Virgo - The Meeting with the Goddess:</h3>
<p>After the trials and transformation comes the meeting with the goddess, a sacred marriage where the hero must reconcile the dual nature of life (or love) and find unity within a greater totality. Ruling Virgo at this stage is Mercury as keeper of boundaries and acting like a bridge between upper and lower world.</p>

<p>Persephone is taken by Hades while picking flowers in a field, then becomes queen of the underworld. In terrible grief, Demeter stops the growing of crops while searching for her daughter, forcing Hades and Zeus to accept the demand for her return. But having eaten a few seeds in the underground, Persephone must stay there part of the year, thus reconciling light and dark, and creating the cycle of the seasons.</p>

<h3 id="libra---the-woman-as-the-temptress">Libra - The Woman as the Temptress:</h3>
<p>Campbell calls this step woman as the temptress, meaning that the hero now has to face the moral problem of being in a world which includes both light and dark. Thus the side of Venus ruling Libra, at this stage, is her divine aspect – favoring beauty, harmony, grace, and the urge to sympathize or unite with others.</p>

<p>Balancing the scales and forces of the universe, Themis – goddess of justice, divine order, law and custom – holds the hero to a high standard, as do the norms of society. Themis is not wrathful, but when she is disregarded Nemesis steps in and brings retribution.  Testing the hero’s integrity, the quest may require going against what others think, say or want, in order to remain true to herself or to the adventure.</p>

<h3 id="scorpio---the-atonement">Scorpio - The Atonement:</h3>
<p>Now comes the darkest point of the journey: atonement with the father, by which the hero breaks past the ego and its fear of death. Governing Scorpio at this stage is Pluto, lord of the underworld associated with depth, power and regeneration, as well as a quietly strategic Mars, pulling the strings beneath the surface.</p>

<p>In the myth of the death of Orion, the hunter boasts to Artemis, goddess of wilderness and the hunt, how he could kill any beast on Earth. Upon hearing this, Gaia sends the giant Scorpion to sting and kill Orion – symbolically sacrificing the hero/ego. Then at the demand of Artemis,  Zeus (the ultimate father figure) places Orion among the stars – a moment of apotheosis by which the hero transcends life.</p>

<h3 id="sagittarius---the-ultimate-boon">Sagittarius - The Ultimate Boon:</h3>
<p>After the release of death, the hero catches a glimpse of eternity in a moment of god-like realization. With a greater understanding of his own being and the world, he gets the ultimate boon: immortality or whatever the quest was about. This stage is under the rulership of Jupiter, supreme god of the sky and largest planet – favoring expansion, healing, fortune, and higher education.</p>

<p>The wise centaur Chiron, teacher of heroes and immortal like his father Cronus, is trained by Apollo in the arts of archery, healing, and prophecy. Ironically, he gets wounded by an arrow dipped in the Hydra’s blood – an accident he does not foresee, and which results in a wound he cannot heal. In pain, Chiron makes a deal with Zeus and willingly gives his immortality to Prometheus.</p>

<h3 id="capricorn---the-return">Capricorn - The Return:</h3>
<p>Having reached the goal, the hero may then refuse to return, be forced to escape in a magic flight, or pulled back to reality with a rescue from without. Ruling Capricorn at this stage, is Saturn and its concerns for goals, time and reality.</p>

<p>Attacked by the monster Typhon, the nature god Pan jumps in a river, and the parts of his body above the water remain a goat while the parts below turn into a fish tail. The sea goat, climbing up on land while pulled down toward the eternal waters of life, shows how difficult it is for the hero to cross the return threshold. Somehow, the connection with the other world must be kept, or there’s a risk of losing the boon when returning on ordinary ground.</p>

<h3 id="aquarius---the-master-of-the-two-worlds">Aquarius - The Master of the Two Worlds:</h3>
<p>The hero’s task is now to become a master of the two worlds, stitching the two together. And what better way to reconcile the everyday and supernatural than the two rulers of Aquarius: the reason and objectivity of Saturn with the genius and unpredictability of Uranus.</p>

<p>The flowing vase of Aquarius pouring cosmic waters onto the world would have been a familiar image at a time when many were employed in the old profession of water carrier. With the myth of Ganymede, the symbol turned into a human cup-bearer serving ambrosia to the gods. Both images reflect the social aspect of this stage, whether bringing the supernatural world back to society and everyday life, or feeding the inner world with outer experiences.</p>

<h3 id="pisces---freedom-to-live">Pisces - Freedom to Live:</h3>
<p>The hero now flows between inner and outer reality, similarly to Pisces. Like the two fishes tied by a cord, Jupiter rules alongside Neptune with the expansive clarity of the sky, and his brother with the fluidity of the sea.</p>

<p>In a similar union of sky and sea, the myth of Pisces has an egg fall into the Euphrates, rolled onto the shore by two fishes, and hatched by doves. Then out of the egg comes Aphrodite in her celestial form. For the hero, this means he’s released from the adventure and gains a new freedom to live. No longer centered in the ego and its fears but established in the Self, the hero lives in the present. The boon brings vitality to those around and restores the world.</p>

<h3 id="in-summary">In Summary:</h3>
<p>In this brief overview of the hero’s journey through the zodiac you can see how this pattern seems to be embedded in the very fabric of our lives: seasons, planets and all. Year after year, Mars is the one to push us on the adventure, while Venus prefers the status quo. Mercury acts as the mentor, Pluto as the dark father. Jupiter brings the boon, Saturn gets us to return.</p>

<p>Even without knowing much about what the planets stand for or the details of each myth, the images of the cards themselves evoke the emotion of the stage it corresponds to. Sagittarius shows the fantastic feeling of getting the ultimate boon, Cancer the mysterious experience of crossing the threshold, Capricorn the balancing act of the return, and so on. And this emotional recognition may be all you need to know where you stand on the journey.</p>

<p>This is one of the more interesting outlines in my collection. I hope it made you think about The Hero’s Journey differently than you have in the past. What are your thoughts? Drop me a comment below.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today’s Thoughts</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/30/Todays-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today’s Thoughts" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/30/Todays-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/30/Todays-Thoughts/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="not-everyday-can-be-a-total-success">Not everyday can be a total success…</h3>

<h3 id="my-negatives">My Negatives:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>I was feeling inadequate comparing my website to that of my husband’s. When I tell you that he is a smart man, I mean it. He knows how to make this shit look amazing.</li>
  <li>Pain was a bit topsy-turvy today.</li>
  <li>I want to post more, however I am exhausted. I may go to bed soon. Again, I have to remind myself that slow and steady wins the rade.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="my-positives">My Positives:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>CARAMEL BANANA GELATO!</li>
  <li>I received a lot of affection from my son today, complete with hugs and kisses and I love yous. It was great.</li>
  <li>As of today I’ve done sixty-eight posts. I feel pretty good about that.</li>
  <li>I have to remind myself that I have enough unpublished content to post for the next five years or more, so I need to do a better job at pacing myself.</li>
  <li>I was thinking about my names post and I think I want to redo it as twenty-six posts instead.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="my-thoughts-on-today">My Thoughts on Today:</h3>
<p>I think I am putting too much pressure on myself regarding this website. I think I just simply need to do whatever I can and stop focusing on the things that didn’t get posted yet. It’s going to become a chore if I continue to see it like I have been. I just need to post what I can and not worry about a stupid made up quota.</p>

<h3 id="questions-to-consider">Questions to Consider:</h3>
<p>What are your thoughts about today?</p>

<p>What are your negatives regarding today?</p>

<p>What are your positives regarding today?</p>

<p>Drop me a comment down below.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My Thoughts on today's successes and failures.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FtBotB - A Romantic Tale</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/ftbotb/2024/10/30/FtBotB-A-Romantic-Tale/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FtBotB - A Romantic Tale" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/ftbotb/2024/10/30/FtBotB%20-A-Romantic-Tale</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/ftbotb/2024/10/30/FtBotB-A-Romantic-Tale/"><![CDATA[<div>


<div class="container" style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <a href="/assets/images/drop.png" data-toggle="lightbox" data-title="">
        <img class="container post-image" alt="" src="/assets/images/drop.png" />

    </a>
    <div class="container figure-caption" style="margin-top: -16px !important; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 16px">
        
    </div>
</div>

</div>

<h2 id="from-the-back-of-the-book">From the Back of the Book:</h2>
<h2 id="working-title">Working Title:</h2>
<p>Drop-offs and Second Chances
 </p>
<h2 id="story-synopsis">Story Synopsis:</h2>
<p>Henley Rodgers thought he had it all - a beautiful wife, one wonderful daughter, and a successful career as an architect. However, when his wife Geanee suddenly falls ill and passes away, Henley’s world comes crashing down. He now struggles to balance grieving and working, with raising his five-year-old daughter Kirby, alone. Just getting her to daycare each morning feels like an impossible task. It’s on these daily preschool drop-offs that Henley first crosses paths with Sparrel Marietti, another single parent. Sparrel too, is rebuilding a life for her young son Kainanin, after narrowly escaping an abusive marriage. Her ex-husband Jaor nearly killed her before she finally worked up the courage to take their son and finally flee. Now, Sparrel constantly looks over her shoulder, worried Jaor will find them. She tries to focus on creating normalcy for Kainanin, but the trauma of abuse hangs over both of them. Sparrel had given up on love or finding happiness again. Yet, every morning when Henley greets her with his trademark “We’ve got to stop meeting like this,” his kindness and playful smile stirs something inside Sparrel. As they chat while they get their kids through the door, she remembers what it feels like to simply enjoy another person’s company. Henley too finds himself looking forward to these brief moments with Sparrel. In the midst of grief, fear and newfound single parenthood, their morning encounters become a bright spot in their days. Henley senses a kindred spirit in Sparrel, as they both rebuild lives shattered by fear and loss. Over time, a deeper affection grows. Henley wonders if he’s ready to move on from his wife’s death and open his heart again. Sparrel questions if she can overcome the scars of abuse to trust another man to be near her and Kainanin. The stakes are raised when Jaor unexpectedly shows up, consumed with possessive rage over his ex-wife finding happiness with someone new. As Sparrel’s worst fears come to pass, Henley must decide if he’s willing to risk it all for a second shot at love. In order to build a new life, they’ll both have to let go of the ghosts of the past, and it starts with dealing with Jaor once and for all. With high emotional stakes, their tentative new connection is put to the ultimate test. However, through their growing love, each begins to heal and glimpse the light of a hopeful future again. Their story explores the complexities of moving on after trauma, while touchingly portraying the redemptive power of human connection.
 </p>
<h2 id="questions">Questions:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Would you purchase and read this novel if you saw it in a bookstore?</li>
  <li>Would you read this novel if it were given to you as a gift?</li>
  <li>How do you feel after having read the synopsis?</li>
  <li>What is your overall opinion of the genre?</li>
  <li>Have you ever read a Romance novel before?</li>
</ol>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="FtBotB" /><category term="writing" /><category term="FtBotB" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Killing Your Darlings</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/exercise/2024/10/30/Killing-Your-Darlings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Killing Your Darlings" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/exercise/2024/10/30/Killing-Your-Darlings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/exercise/2024/10/30/Killing-Your-Darlings/"><![CDATA[<p>The decision to kill your protagonist in the middle of your story is a bold and impactful narrative choice that can have profound implications for the plot, character development, and thematic exploration. While it’s not a decision to be taken lightly, there are scenarios where it can be a great idea. Let’s explore the reasons why this might be one of those times:</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Character Growth and Transformation:
Killing the protagonist mid-story can provide a unique opportunity for character growth and transformation. It forces other characters to step into leadership roles, confront their own limitations, and adapt to the challenges previously shouldered by the protagonist. This can lead to powerful arcs of personal development and self-discovery.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Plot Twists and Unpredictability:
The death of the protagonist is a dramatic plot twist that can take readers by surprise. This level of unpredictability can keep the story engaging and captivate the audience’s attention. It challenges conventional storytelling norms and subverts expectations, making the narrative more memorable.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Exploration of Themes:
The protagonist’s death can serve as a vehicle for exploring profound themes such as sacrifice, legacy, mortality, and the enduring impact of one’s actions. It invites readers to contemplate the protagonist’s legacy and the enduring power of their ideals.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Test of Resilience:
When the protagonist is no longer present to guide and protect, other characters must demonstrate their resilience and resourcefulness. Their ability to carry on the protagonist’s mission or values can be a testament to the strength of the human spirit in the face of adversity.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Redefining Heroism:
Killing the protagonist can redefine the concept of heroism within the narrative. It challenges the notion that heroism is confined to a single individual and highlights the collective strength of a group or community coming together to achieve a common goal.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Emotional Impact:
The protagonist’s death can evoke powerful emotions in readers and characters alike. Grief, loss, and determination in the face of tragedy can resonate deeply with the audience, creating a strong emotional connection to the story.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Compelling Conflict:
The absence of the protagonist can create compelling conflicts among other characters and adversaries. It can shift the dynamics of power, alliances, and goals, adding layers of complexity to the narrative.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Exploration of Indispensability:
Imagining the protagonist dead is a way to test just how indispensable they are to the story and the world they inhabit. It challenges the notion that the protagonist is irreplaceable and allows the narrative to explore the consequences of their absence.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>While killing the protagonist mid-story is a daring narrative choice, it can lead to a richer, more thought-provoking, and emotionally resonant storytelling experience. It challenges both characters and readers to grapple with the hero’s absence and consider the enduring impact of their actions. When executed thoughtfully, this decision can elevate your story to new heights, making it a memorable and impactful journey for your audience.</p>

<p>The Exercise:</p>
<ol>
  <li>
    <p>Name three characters that COULD step into your protagonist’s place if necessary, and then write a short paragraph explaining why they’d be the best person for the job and then write a short paragraph explaining what shortcomings might preclude them from the job.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Brainstorm three plot twists that would arise due to your protagonist’s death.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Write a short paragraph explaining your protagonist’s ideals and how these ideals will created a long lasting legacy from now (the moment of their death) until the end of the story.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Take two or more of your remaining main and secondary characters and write an example scene showcasing a test of resilience after the protagonist’s death occurs.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Write a paragraph defining what heroism meant when the protagonist was still alive and then write another paragraph redefining what heroism means now that they are dead. What has changed and what will remain the same?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>List ten emotions that the protagonist’s closest family member, friend or ally is feeling after their death and then write a a group of scenes with dialogue showcasing all ten of those emotions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Brainstorm five different conflicts that could potentially arise due to the protagonist’s untimely death. What is at the core of these conflicts aside from the protagonist’s absence?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>What are five immediate consequences of the protagonist’s death? With these five immediate consequences in play, do you as the author still see a path forward for your story? If you do, what does that path look like?</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<p>Consider the Following:</p>
<ol>
  <li>Ripple Effects on Minor Characters:
Consider how the protagonist’s absence might affect minor characters in your story. How do characters with smaller roles respond to the news of the protagonist’s death or absence? How might their lives change in subtle or significant ways?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that showcases minor characters finding out and reacting to the protagonist’s death. Write about what they do and say to one another in the immediate aftermath. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Minor and Primary Antagonists’ Reaction:
Explore how the minor antagonist or antagonistic force in your story reacts to the protagonist’s absence. Is the emotional reaction displayed by the minor antagonist, the same in front of their forces as it is in private? Do they believe the protagonist is truly gone, or do they harbor suspicions? Do they view this as a victory or a setback? How does this impact their plans and actions? How do they adjust their plans and strategies in light of this development? What new challenges or opportunities does this create for the minor antagonist? Do they underestimate the remaining characters resolve?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that showcases minor antagonist and his or her forces finding out and reacting to the protagonist’s death. Write about what they do and say to one another in the immediate aftermath. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<p>Explore how the primary antagonist or antagonistic force in your story reacts to the protagonist’s absence. Is the emotional reaction displayed by the primary antagonist, the same in front of their forces as it is in private? Do they believe the protagonist is truly gone, or do they harbor suspicions? Do they view this as a victory or a setback? How does this impact their plans and actions? How do they adjust their plans and strategies in light of this development? What new challenges or opportunities does this create for the primary antagonist? Do they underestimate the remaining characters resolve?</p>

<p>Write a scene that showcases the primary antagonist and his or her forces finding out and reacting to the protagonist’s death. Write about what they do and say to one another in the immediate aftermath. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Unfulfilled Goals and Dreams:
Think about the protagonist’s unfulfilled goals, dreams, or promises. What aspirations did they have that now remain unrealized? How do other characters in the story attempt to carry on these aspirations, if at all? Do any characters feel a sense of responsibility to fulfill the protagonist’s unfinished business?</li>
</ol>

<p>List five of the biggest unfulfilled goals, dreams, or promises that the protagonist failed to accomplish due to their death. Now, write a scene where a remaining character fulfills one or more of the goals/dreams/promises in the name of the protagonist. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Uncovering Secrets:
Consider whether the protagonist’s death or absence might lead to the revelation of hidden secrets or information. Are there truths that come to light in the protagonist’s absence? How do these revelations impact the remaining characters? Do any secrets hold the key to continuing the protagonist’s mission?</li>
</ol>

<p>Brainstorm five different secrets that could be revealed after the protagonist’s untimely death. Review each one and select the one you feel fits best and then write a scene about the big reveal. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>New Leadership Dynamics:
Consider how the protagonist’s death or absence reshapes the leadership dynamics within their group or community. Now, we already discussed who would take on the role, so let’s delve a bit deeper. How does their leadership style differ from the protagonist’s? What are the main challenges and conflicts that arise as new leaders emerge?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that showcases the new leader’s skills and in contrast, their shortcomings amid the new emerging conflicts and challenges. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Impact on Personal Relationships:
Examine how the protagonist’s death or absence affects personal relationships among the remaining characters. Are there rifts or tensions that emerge due to grief, blame, or differing reactions to the loss? How do characters navigate these changes in their interpersonal connections?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene showcasing the emerging conflict that arises as a direct result of the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Legacy and Memorials:
Contemplate how the protagonist is remembered and honored in the story world. Are there efforts to preserve their legacy, such as memorials, monuments, or traditions? How do characters grapple with the protagonist’s lasting impact on their lives and the world around them?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene showcasing how other character memorialize or remember the protagonist after their death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Unresolved Storylines:
Think about any unresolved storylines or plot threads related to the protagonist. What loose ends remain in the wake of their death or absence? How do characters address these unfinished business aspects? Do they seek closure or resolution?</li>
</ol>

<p>Go through your outline and list all of the unresolved storylines. Try to imagine who that remains, continue where the protagonist left off, and could resolve these storylines. Now, write a scene for each unresolved storyline that showcases the new character picking up the protagonist’s torch. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Themes of Grief and Healing:
Delve into the themes of grief and healing within the story. How do characters cope with the loss of the protagonist, and what stages of grief do they experience? Are there moments of catharsis or reconciliation as characters come to terms with their emotions?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene showcasing a group of pivotal characters in grief over the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Evolution of the Antagonist:
Consider how the protagonist’s death or absence impacts the main antagonist. Does it embolden them, leading to more aggressive actions? What do these more aggressive actions look like? What are the immediate consequences of these more aggressive actions? Does it create doubt and uncertainty? What does this doubt and uncertainty look like? What are the immediate consequences for this doubt and uncertainty? How does both the minor and the primary antagonist (as well as any other notable enemies) adapt to the changing dynamics in their pursuit of their goals?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene showcasing how the primary antagonist is handling the aftermath of the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<p>Write a scene showcasing how the minor antagonist is handling the aftermath of the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<p>Write a scene showcasing how other enemies are handling the aftermath of the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Protagonist’s Influence on Allies:
Examine how the protagonist’s influence continues to shape the actions and decisions of their allies and supporters. Do characters carry forward the protagonist’s ideals and mission? How does this influence their choices?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that showcases a year or more into the future and how the protagonist continues to influence the lives of people who knew them. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Quest for Closure:
Explore whether any characters embark on a quest or mission related to the protagonist’s death or absence. Is there a search for answers, justice, or redemption? How does this quest drive the narrative forward and impact character development?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene where an individual character who was close to the protagonist goes on a personal journey to seek closure surrounding the death of the protagonist. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>New Alliances and Conflicts:
Examine how characters form new alliances or rivalries in response to the protagonist’s death or absence. Are there unexpected partnerships or betrayals? How do these new relationships affect the overall narrative?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that examines new alliances or rivalries that form as a direct result of the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Impact on Secondary Characters:
Delve into the experiences and reactions of secondary characters who were not part of the protagonist’s inner circle. How do they perceive the protagonist’s legacy? How are they affected by the protagonist’s death or absence indirectly?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that showcases secondary characters finding out and reacting to the protagonist’s death. Write about what they do and say to one another in the immediate aftermath. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Flashbacks and Memories:
Consider using flashbacks and memories as storytelling devices to keep the protagonist’s presence alive in the narrative. How do characters remember and honor the protagonist through these moments? What insights do these glimpses into the past provide?</li>
</ol>

<p>Create a flashback scene via a story that a pivotal character is telling to someone or a group of people, about the protagonist or a special event that the protagonist was a part of. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Protagonist’s Influence on Society:
Explore how the protagonist’s actions and beliefs continue to influence the broader society within the story world. Are there movements, ideologies, or changes in societal norms that stem from the protagonist’s legacy?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene that showcases how the protagonist continues to influence the lives of people who have never met them, a generation or more in the future. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Unintended Consequences:
Think about any unintended consequences that arise as a result of the protagonist’s death or absence. Are there unforeseen challenges or benefits that emerge? How do characters adapt to these unexpected developments? Using the Law of Unintended Consequences, list five consequences that could arise.</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene showcasing the law of unintended consequences surrounding the protagonist’s death. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<ol>
  <li>The Possibility of Resurrection or Return:
Contemplate whether there is a possibility of the protagonist’s resurrection or return in the story. How do characters grapple with the hope or uncertainty surrounding this potential event? Does it drive their actions and decisions?</li>
</ol>

<p>Write a scene (however hypothetical) showcasing how other pivotal characters might seek to have the fates reverse their decision and bring the protagonist back to life. Seek to answer all of the proposed questions from the prompt.</p>

<p>The Scene:
Consider these Questions:
Alternately, if everyone wrongly believed your protagonist was dead, what would they suddenly be free to do?
How long would they wait to reveal that they’re still alive?
What would their opponents do and what would they say once they find out that the protagonist is still alive?
What would their friends and family do and what would they say once they find out that the protagonist is still alive?</p>

<p>A False Death: Considering the above questions, you are now going to write four different scenes answering each of the provided questions above.</p>

<p>Now, write a eulogy for your protagonist from another character’s point of view. Could that character say any of those things while the hero is alive?</p>

<p>The Chosen One:
The Eulogy:
Now, jot down your character’s last will and testament. Would they want to be buried or cremated, and where do they wish their remains to go? What would their tombstone read? Who would get their stuff? Who would be omitted from receiving anything and why are they omitted? How do the people who were omitted react to being omitted? Would the people included be satisfied with what they receive? Would they be jealous of what other people receive? What conflicts arise as a direct consequence of the way the will is written?</p>

<p>The Written Will:
Lastly, consider options short of literal death: prison, coma, exile, alien stasis. Anything that takes your protagonist out of action, albeit temporarily, can work. What would be your first choice here? Why would it be their first choice? Once you’ve figured out the answer to this question, write a scene showcasing your decision.</p>

<p>I know that this exercise is a doozy, but I feel it is well worth it to get this out on to a page. How do you feel about killing your darlings? Drop me a comment down below.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="exercise" /><category term="writing" /><category term="exercise" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The decision to kill your protagonist in the middle of your story is a bold and impactful narrative choice that can have profound implications for the plot, character development, and thematic exploration. While it’s not a decision to be taken lightly, there are scenarios where it can be a great idea. Let’s explore the reasons why this might be one of those times:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beat of the Day - Protagonist Issues - A Full Circle Sequence</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/10/30/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Protagonist-Issues-A-Full-Circle-Sequence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beat of the Day - Protagonist Issues - A Full Circle Sequence" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/10/30/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Protagonist-Issues-A-Full-Circle-Sequence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/botd/2024/10/30/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Protagonist-Issues-A-Full-Circle-Sequence/"><![CDATA[<p>This is a full circle sequence.</p>

<p>It starts with the protagonist being busy being heroic, but they’re struggling and their struggles will lead them to make mistakes, both big and small. Some, having long lasting consequences. After the mistakes are made, no matter their size, the protagonist tries to ignore the mistakes in favor of making some sort of headway. It could be small, large or fleeting. This could involve cornering an adversary,  the main villain, or something completely inconsequential. Then the protagonist finds themselves almost buried in his troubles. These troubles could be physical, mental or emotional. These troubles need to nearly consume the protagonist, but the consequences of the paralyzation need to match that of the troubles themselves. At some point, the protagonist finally defeats their paralyzation and extricates themselves using their own skills, training and brawn, or help from friends, strangers or even adversaries. Lastly, and completing the circle, the protagonist makes a deliberate choice to continue, even if the chances of success are slim.</p>

<h3 id="heroic-tangles">Heroic Tangles:</h3>
<p>The protagonist is busy being heroic, but he’s struggling and his struggles will lead him to make mistakes, both big and small. Some, having long lasting consequences. This folder can be placed multiple times in the same section or multiple sections, depending on the need too.</p>

<h3 id="heroic-rallying">Heroic Rallying:</h3>
<p>The protagonist makes some sort of headway. It could be small, large or fleeting. This could involve cornering an adversary,  the main villain, or something completely inconsequential. This folder can be placed multiple times in the same section or multiple sections, depending on the need too.</p>

<h3 id="entombed-in-imperilment">Entombed in Imperilment:</h3>
<p>This is the time where you need to get the protagonist almost buried in his troubles. These troubles could be physical, mental or emotional. These troubles need to nearly consume the protagonist, but the consequences of the paralyzation need to match that of the troubles themselves. This folder can be placed multiple times in the same section or multiple sections, depending on the need too.</p>

<h3 id="quashing-imperilment">Quashing Imperilment:</h3>
<p>The protagonist defeats their paralyzation and extricates themselves using their own skills, training and brawn, or help from friends, strangers or even adversaries. This folder can be placed multiple times in the same section or multiple sections, depending on the need too.</p>

<h3 id="seizing-the-sword">Seizing the Sword:</h3>
<p>The protagonist makes a deliberate choice to continue, even if the chances of success are slim.</p>

<p>This isn’t just one beat, so it’s not truly a beat of the day, but at the same time with only five beats, it’s not really a full fleshed outline either. Let me know what you would consider it to be. Drop me a comment below.</p>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="BotD" /><category term="BotD" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a full circle sequence.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Character Driven Hero’s Journey</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/30/A-Character-Driven-Heroes-Journey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Character Driven Hero’s Journey" /><published>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/30/A-Character-Driven-Heroes-Journey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing/outline/2024/10/30/A-Character-Driven-Heroes-Journey/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="a-character-driven-journey">A Character Driven Journey:</h3>
<p>In narratology and comparative mythology, the hero’s journey, or the monomyth, is the common template of stories that involve a hero who goes on an adventure, is victorious in a decisive crisis, and comes home changed or transformed.</p>

<p>This however, isn’t like the typical Hero’s Journey though. This outline is a bit more concentrated in that it only has thirteen beats, whereas the traditional Hero’s Journey outline usually contains anywhere between twenty and thirty beats.</p>

<h3 id="im-incomplete">I’m Incomplete:</h3>
<p>This is the beat where you’re going to establish your protagonist’s wants,  needs and desires. This is also where you’re going to showcase your protagonist’s struggle inside their “ordinary world”.</p>

<h3 id="im-unsettled">I’m Unsettled:</h3>
<p>This is where an outside force first appears (e.g. an invitation or a threat). It typically doesn’t immediately include the primary antagonist, although whatever happens inside this beat should be at the very least tangentially linked to them in some way.</p>

<h3 id="im-resistant">I’m Resistant:</h3>
<p>This beat is typically called “refusal of the call,” “refusing the call” or something similar, and it is when your protagonist is going to adamantly refuse to do the things that have been asked of them, albeit temporarily.</p>

<h3 id="im-encouraged">I’m Encouraged:</h3>
<p>This beat is when your protagonist is going to be pushed (by their own actions, someone else’s actions or someone else’s words) onto the right path or direction.</p>

<h3 id="im-committed">I’m Committed:</h3>
<p>This is the beat where your protagonist burns the bridges (these bridges could be literal, figurative or both) behind them, so that no matter what they do or say now, there’s absolutely no turning back to their former life.</p>

<h3 id="im-disoriented">I’m Disoriented:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist must navigate towards their goal, facing unfamiliar challenges and new rules.</p>

<h3 id="im-inauthentic">I’m Inauthentic:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist does their best to ignore their own critical flaws that impede them from furthering their journey and ultimately accomplishing their goals.</p>

<h3 id="im-confronted">I’m Confronted:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist realizes that they must face their critical flaws or they’re at risk of losing everything and everyone that they love.</p>

<h3 id="im-terrified">I’m Terrified:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist realizes that they must face their greatest enemy even if it means that they’re at risk of losing everything and everyone that they love.</p>

<h3 id="im-reborn">I’m Reborn:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist starts to demonstrate that they’ve begun to change their ways, having addressed the critical flaws.</p>

<h3 id="im-desperate">I’m Desperate:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist hits a major roadblock and must do throw everything they possess at it in order to jump over it.</p>

<h3 id="im-decisive">I’m Decisive:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist must choose between their wants and their needs.</p>

<h3 id="im-complete">I’m Complete:</h3>
<p>This is when the protagonist gets what they deserve, based on their previous choice.</p>

<p>Are you a plotter or a pantser? If you’re a plotter what outlining process suits you best. Perhaps it’s one that I’ve not seen or worked with (if you couldn’t tell, I’m a bit of an outline addict, and I have collected over a thousand outlines over the years). I am very interested in hearing all about your process. So, drop me a comment down below. Let’s chat outlining.</p>

<!-- signature -->

<div style="display: block; align-content: center">
    <img style="width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" alt="" src="/assets/images/kojika-signature.png" />
</div>]]></content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><category term="writing" /><category term="outline" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Character Driven Journey: In narratology and comparative mythology, the hero’s journey, or the monomyth, is the common template of stories that involve a hero who goes on an adventure, is victorious in a decisive crisis, and comes home changed or transformed.]]></summary></entry></feed>