<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-10-23T20:13:56-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">FtBotB - An Amish Romance</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/ftbotb/2024/10/23/From-the-Back-of-the-Book-An-Amish-Romance/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FtBotB - An Amish Romance" /><published>2024-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/ftbotb/2024/10/23/From-the-Back-of-the-Book-An-Amish-Romance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/ftbotb/2024/10/23/From-the-Back-of-the-Book-An-Amish-Romance/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-the-back-of-the-book&quot;&gt;From the Back of the Book:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working Title: Stitched Hearts - A Tale of Love, Faith, and Fabric:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Story Synopsis: Miriam Lapp lived a simple life in her Amish community, finding joy and purpose in quilting beautiful fabrics together. Though she longed to express her creativity in new ways, Miriam knew that stepping outside the norms of her faith would bring instant condemnation from her community. That all changed when Miriam met Aldus Budai, a talented English fabric designer from the New York City. Aldus instantly saw the potential in Miriam’s skilled hands and discerning eye, and asked her to collaborate with him on a line of quilted dresses. Once home, she asked her mother if she could help a woman sew some dresses in the city, for extra money. Against her better judgment, her mother allowed Miriam to take the job. Miriam was wary at first, but the opportunity to meld her talents with Aldus’ modern aesthetic was too tempting to pass up. As they worked together, an unexpected bond began to form. Aldus was drawn to Miriam’s gentle spirit and devotion to her art, so unlike the ambitious, frenetic world he inhabited. Too, Miriam found inspiration in Aldus’ courage to follow his passions without limitation. Soon, their partnership sparked into something more - a romance that defied all convention. However, as their feelings deepened, opposition arose on all sides. Miriam’s community scolded and shunned her for lying about her job, keeping her association with an English man a secret and straying from her people’s traditions. Meanwhile, Aldus’ cosmopolitan circle raised eyebrows at his interest in a modest, reserved Amish woman. Even worse, Miriam and Aldus themselves struggled to reconcile their disparate values and lifestyles. The differences between their worlds were thrown into stark view. Miriam wrestled with guilt over disappointing her community and doubts about leaving her heritage behind. Aldus questioned whether he could fit into Miriam’s insular, rule-bound community. Both agonized over whether a relationship between an Amish woman and outsider man could ever last. In the end, Miriam and Aldus’ shared passion for bringing beauty into the world through fabric arts overcame all obstacles. They dared to follow their hearts, even at the risk of being shunned permanently by those they loved. Their story wove together two worlds, proving that with trust and understanding, an unlikely love could flourish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you purchase and read this novel if you saw it in a bookstore?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you read this novel if it were given to you as a gift?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do you feel after having read the synopsis?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is your overall opinion of the genre?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have you ever read an Amish Romance before?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="FtBotB" /><category term="writing," /><category term="FtBotB" /><summary type="html">From the Back of the Book: Working Title: Stitched Hearts - A Tale of Love, Faith, and Fabric:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Modified Beat Sheet - Part One</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/outline,/writing/2024/10/23/My-Modified-Beat-Sheet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Modified Beat Sheet - Part One" /><published>2024-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/outline,/writing/2024/10/23/My-Modified-Beat-Sheet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/outline,/writing/2024/10/23/My-Modified-Beat-Sheet/">&lt;p&gt;Before I start showing you this particular outline, I want to explain how it came into existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is my main outline, it’s actually the outline that made me fall in love with outlining. I created this back in 2009 because I really didn’t like the half-assed outlines that I continued to find online. None of them worked well enough for me to where I was producing a polished, finished story in the end, so I created this. I am well aware that it’s extra. In fact fairly soon it might even attain an epic status of extra. Anyway, it may be extra, and it may become more extra soon, but it’s what works for me. If you like it, use it and throw an email my way to tell me how it’s helped you flesh your stories out. I would love to hear all about your adventure using this outline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First Note: The Trials can be major or minor and have three different, for lack of a better term, identifiers. Too, they show up right after each major beat of the outline. This is one of the many tests the protagonist will undertake throughout the story. He/She will be subjected to a painful, or at least an unpleasant, usually dangerous experience. The test could be one of life or death. This is all about risk, motivation, conflict and resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second Note: The Mini-Quests are similar to quests and sub-quests in that they can be groups of interrelated tasks that can be completed for rewards such as new items, new skills, and new experiences. Ideally, this section should contain at least one-hundred pages or more and it should contain at least twenty-seven-thousand-five-hundred words or more. A mini-quest is a small diversion on the character’s path. If the ultimate goal is to save the princess, then a mini-quest may be to find the magic phone book to look up her address, or to return to your castle because you can’t remember whether or not you closed the draw-bridge. Add a few mini-quests to slow the pace and to develop character and you’ll have earned yourself five-hundred to a thousand words each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each trials and mini-quests will be considered one of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Random) Internal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Random) Antagonistic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Random) External&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Consequential) Internal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Consequential) Antagonistic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Consequential) External&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Inconsequential) Internal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Inconsequential) Antagonistic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minor (Inconsequential) External&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Random) Internal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Random) Antagonistic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Random) External&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Consequential) Internal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Consequential) Antagonistic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Consequential) External&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Inconsequential) Internal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Inconsequential) Antagonistic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Major (Inconsequential) External&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, on to the actual outline! An additional note, this is a very hefty outline with one-hundred amd seventy-four individual beats. Like I said, it’s extra. I have separated this outline into four different sections. However, you can modify this for your own use, if you so choose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;act-i&quot;&gt;Act I:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Introduction: Introduce the protagonist, hook the reader, and use foreshadowing, the establishment of some stakes and a major goal to begin establishing empathy (but not necessarily likability) for the protagonist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Opening Image: This beat sets the tone, mood type, and scope of the project. This is a “before” snapshot. The “Opening Image” of the story needs to reflect the theme. To know what this should be, the writer must know what the Theme is first. It is a visual that represents the struggle and tone of the story. A snapshot of the protagonist’s problem, before the adventure begins. Try to startle readers with the first line. Shocking readers immediately with a jarring moment, visual, or confession will get them excited to read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Opening Scene: A Good Opening Scene Starts With a Problem. The opening scene problem doesn’t have to be part of the core conflict. It can be something inherent to the world the protagonist lives in. Maybe he’s being chased by monsters, or dodging a nasty boss, or even arguing with his ex-spouse. Whatever a typical issue is for the protagonist can work in an opening scene. It’s also fine if the opening problem is part of the core conflict and gets readers into the main plot right away. Whatever the problem may be, look for ways to set the protagonist on the plot path, using the opening scene problem as a bridge to get to the rest of the plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) Stating the Theme: A (or some) secondary character(s) poses/pose a/some question(s) or statement(s) to the protagonist that become(s) the overall theme of the story. It’s what the story is about, the message, the truth. Usually it’s spoken to the protagonist or they bear witness to it. Though they don’t yet understand it, it takes a personal experience or context to support it. What is Theme? Theme is the meaning behind or revealed by story. Theme in literature is often varied and hidden. Sometimes a reader can get through an entire book and not realize what the author meant, and while convention will tell you that’s unacceptable, I’m telling you that it is one-hundred percent allowable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Big Hook Moment: Something that creates a question the reader wants an answer to, or an itch that needs to be scratched; doesn’t need context with the protagonist’s needs or stakes. The hook comes in many forms, but stripped down to its lowest common denominator, the hook is nothing more or less than a question. If we can pique our readers’ curiosity, we’ve got them. It’s as simple as that. The beginning of every story should present character, setting, and conflict. But, in themselves, none of these represent a hook. We’ve created a hook only when we’ve persuaded readers to ask the general question, “What will happen?” because we’ve also persuaded them to ask a more specific question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Setup: Introduce or hint at as many characters in “A” Story as you possibly can (at least all of the main players in the story) and plant character ties to be addressed later on. During the setup, we see the protagonist in three places: home, work and play. Expand on the “before” snapshot. Present the main character’s world as it is, and what is missing in their life. Try to use backstory for an important character introductions. Telling a character’s history upfront immediately gives readers a sense of formative experiences and character psychology. If an author chooses this approach to introducing a character, avoid the info dump. Keep backstory relevant to the character’s story arc and their present circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Catalyst: A catalyst sentence precedes action or sets something important in motion. This is the life changing event that effectively knocks down the house of cards for the protagonist(s), secondary and support characters. Something comes into the protagonist’s life and calls him/her to action. He/She must perform some insane act and or leave, physically or metaphorically to an unfamiliar place. This is the moment where life as it is, changes. It is the telegram, the act of catching your loved-one cheating, allowing a monster onboard the ship, meeting the love of your life, etc. The “before” world is no more big changes are underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Inciting Incident: The Inciting Incident is how you get your characters to do something. It’s the doorway through which they can’t return. Then, the whole of the story takes care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Initial Internal Conflict: An internal conflict occurs when a character in literature experiences tension within themselves. Internal conflict is the opposite of external conflict, which occurs when a character faces outside oppositional forces, such as another character or an act of nature. Sometimes referred to as man vs. self, internal conflicts involve the character experiencing opposing needs, desires or values. Sometimes, these battles represent conflict between a character’s mind or subjective knowledge and their heart or feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) Initial External Conflict: The Initial External Conflict is a key event that sets the plot in motion and forces the protagonist to take action. It is often the inciting incident that disrupts the protagonist’s ordinary world and compels them to embark on their journey or confront the central problem of the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Woven-In Backstory: Ask yourself this question: What happened before the inciting incident that we must know to understand the story? Behind every well-developed novel lies an important backstory—but including too much of it too soon can halt your story’s momentum. Here’s how to know what to reveal and when. Backstory refers to the characters’ history and other story elements that underlie the situation at the start of the book. Backstory helps to establish the setting and makes the reader care about what happens to the characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Debate: This is the point of no return. This is when and where the protagonist(s), sometimes in conjunction with secondary and support character make a very important choice or a series of very important choices. The protagonist resists the call to action. There is a debate (right after the answer/question in the “Inciting Incident”), either internally or externally, where the protagonist is still resisting the call. Change is scary and for a moment, or a brief number of moments, the main character doubts the journey they must take. Can he/she face this challenge? Does he/she have what it takes? Should he/she go at all? It is the last chance for the hero to chicken out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The First Plot Point: The first major plot point changes everything. This is the point of no return for the characters. The first plot point is the moment when the setup ends, and the character crosses his personal Rubicon. But this isn’t just an event that happens to him. This is an event that either incorporates or is directly followed by the character’s reacting in a strong and irrevocable way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Illusion of Perfect: This is a time where characters have a feeling of being safer than one really is. It is the act of being insecurely secure. The protagonist has a false sense of security and is trapped in a negative world that stops her growth. She avoids the reality of her situation by using a coping strategy. Security is an interesting subject that follows us from before our birth until the day we die. Our entire life is composed of security, insecurity, and a false sense of security that often confuses the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) Fun and Games: The promise of the premise/the heart of the story/all about having fun. The entertaining aspects of the story’s premise are explored–highlighting the main character’s unlikeliness for this “upside down world”–which is fun to watch, but NOT fun for the main character, who is essentially in HELL until the end of the story. It’s where we aren’t as concerned with the forward progress of the story—the stakes won’t be raised until the midpoint—as we are concerned with having fun. We take a break from the stakes of the story and see what the idle a is about; we see the promise of the premise and need not see anything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Turning Point: A cliffhanger, a moment where the story is taken in a new direction and we wonder what will happen next. A Turning Point may accomplish a variety of functions. It turns the actions around in a new direction, raises the central question/problem again, and makes us wonder about the answer. It’s often a moment of decision or commitment on the part of the main character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The Allied Attack: This is when a trusted ally confronts the protagonist about their increasing desperation and immorality, and thoroughly questions their behavior. During the drive, the hero is losing to the opponent and becoming desperate. When he starts taking immoral steps to succeed, the ally confronts him. At this moment, the ally becomes the conscience of the hero, saying in effect, “I’m trying to help you reach your goal, but the way you’re doing it is wrong.” Typically, the hero tries to defend his actions and does not accept the ally’s criticism. The attack by the ally provides the story with the second level of conflict (hero versus opposition is the first). The ally’s attack increases the pressure on the hero and forces and forces him to begin questioning his values and way of acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(major beat) The First Juxtaposition: An act or instance of placing two elements close together or side by side. This is often done in order to compare/contrast the two, to show similarities or differences, etc. Various forms of juxtaposition occur in literature, where two images that are otherwise not commonly brought together appear side by side or structurally close together, thereby forcing the reader to stop and reconsider the meaning of the text through the contrasting images, ideas, motifs, etc. More broadly, an author can juxtapose contrasting types of characters, such as a protagonist and an antagonist working together to achieve a common objective from very different motivations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Trial (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Mini-Quest (see above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TO BE CONTINUED…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="outline," /><category term="writing" /><category term="outline." /><category term="writing" /><summary type="html">Before I start showing you this particular outline, I want to explain how it came into existence.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Today’s Feelings</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/23/Today's-Feelings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Today’s Feelings" /><published>2024-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/23/Today's-Feelings</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/23/Today's-Feelings/">&lt;p&gt;I am overall in a good mood today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My pain levels are a bit high, but I am very happy that I did not require a nap today. I’ve gotten some transfers and writing done. I was able to play with my kids too. So, I would consider this a sucessful day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t eaten very much today. It’s just so hard to eat, these days. I didn’t have the tube feed on today, and I think that, that was a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to tomorrow being as good as today or better. Oh, and FUCK CANCER…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;signature –&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">I am overall in a good mood today.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Exhaustion is Real</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/21/The-Exhuastion-Is-Real/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Exhaustion is Real" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/21/The-Exhuastion-Is-Real</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/life/2024/10/21/The-Exhuastion-Is-Real/">&lt;p&gt;First things first… I apologize…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been twenty days since I’ve posted some real content. I apologize, my body has been so tired that simply being awake was a battle. The battle isn’t over either. However, I am going to be making a real effort to post through the exhaustion. Luckily for me, I have a lot of ready content to cull from. I’ve already made three posts today, so I’m doing better than I have been these past twenty days. So, I’m off to do The Beat of the Day, post an Outline and look at a writing system to review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="Life" /><category term="Life" /><summary type="html">First things first… I apologize…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seventy-Seven Individual Character Archetypes</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/archetypes,/characters/2024/10/21/Seventy-Seven-Character-Archetypes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seventy-Seven Individual Character Archetypes" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/archetypes,/characters/2024/10/21/Seventy-Seven-Character-Archetypes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/archetypes,/characters/2024/10/21/Seventy-Seven-Character-Archetypes/">&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of seventy-seven character archetypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Rogue With a Heart of Gold: Seemingly selfish or aloof, this character eventually reveals a deep sense of honor and willingness to risk all for the right cause. Example: Han Solo from Star Wars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Rebellious Hero: Rejects societal norms and bravely defies authority, driven by a deeper understanding or morality that others might not see. Example: Katniss Everdeen from The Hunger Games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Disguised Stranger: Someone who hides their true identity, often revealing themselves in a pivotal moment, providing a dramatic twist to the story. Example: Aragorn from The Lord of the Rings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Wandering Bard: Roaming from place to place, this character is both a teller of tales and a player in them, often influencing events subtly. Example: Kvothe from The Name of the Wind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Broken Optimist: Once believed in the best outcomes, but life events have jaded them, setting them on a path to regain their optimism. Example: Ted Lasso from Ted Lasso.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Gentle Giant: Imposing in stature but soft at heart, their physical strength is in contrast with their gentle nature. Example: Hodor from Game of Thrones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Reluctant Warrior: Prefers peace and avoids conflict, but when pushed, displays unmatched skill and determination in combat. Example: Samwise Gamgee from The Lord of the Rings.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Seeker of Vengeance: Motivated primarily by revenge, their journey often questions the costs and morality of their quest. Example: Inigo Montoya from The Princess Bride.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Cursed Wanderer: A character doomed to roam, often bearing a curse or a tragic past that denies them rest or respite. Example: The Flying Dutchman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Melancholic Dreamer: Often lost in thought, this archetype is more in tune with the ethereal and the artistic, sometimes to their detriment. Example: Jay Gatsby from The Great Gatsby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Enigmatic Scholar: Holds vast knowledge and is often reserved, revealing depths in carefully chosen moments. Example: Trelawney from Harry Potter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fallen Hero: Once revered but brought down by a flaw or twist of fate, their journey is one of redemption or tragedy. Example: Anakin Skywalker from Star Wars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Scheming Artisan: Talented in their craft but uses it for dubious or malicious ends, weaving complex plots. Example: Iago from Othello.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Leader with a Dark Secret: Exudes confidence and gathers followers, but hides a crucial aspect of their past or intentions. Example: President Snow from The Hunger Games.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Outlaw Out for Justice: Operates outside the law, but for noble or just causes, often challenging what’s deemed “legal” and “moral.” Example: Robin Hood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Silent Observer: Speaks little, but their actions or the few words they do utter hold significant weight or insight. Example: Boo Radley from To Kill a Mockingbird.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ethereal Mystic: Connected deeply with the spiritual or supernatural, their knowledge often guides or warns the main characters. Example: The Ancient One from Doctor Strange.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Enigmatic Stranger: Appears unexpectedly, offering assistance or posing challenges, their true intentions and identity a mystery. Example: The Continental Op from Dashiell Hammett’s detective stories.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Puppet Master: Operates from the shadows, manipulating events and characters to achieve their goals. Example: Varys from Game of Thrones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Defiant Artist: Uses their art to challenge norms, make political statements, or rebel against established order. Example: Edmond Dantès from The Count of Monte Cristo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Nurturing Guardian: Offers emotional, spiritual, or physical protection and guidance, often at the risk of their own well-being. Example: Molly Weasley from Harry Potter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dreamer Awakened: Once lived in their own world or fantasies, but a pivotal event forces them to confront reality. Example: Walter Mitty from… The Secret Life of Walter Mitty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fallen Noble: Was once in a position of power or prestige but lost it, now seeks redemption or a return to former glory. Example: Prince Zuko from Avatar: The Last Airbender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Merchant with a Code: Engages in commerce (sometimes illicit), but operates based on a set of unbreakable personal ethics. Example: Han Solo from Star Wars before he joins the Rebellion.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Silent Observer: Watches events unfold, rarely taking direct action, but their understanding or revelation becomes key to the story’s resolution. Example: Boo Radley from To Kill a Mockingbird.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Charming Scoundrel: Engages in morally ambiguous or outright criminal activities but does so with charm and wit. Example: Neal Caffrey from White Collar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ethical Adversary: Opposes the protagonist but does so out of personal honor or a conflicting sense of what’s right. Example: Killmonger from Black Panther.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Reviled Martyr: Sacrifices for the greater good but receives scorn or indifference rather than praise from the masses. Example: John Proctor from The Crucible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mirror Twin: Bears an uncanny resemblance in appearance or character to another, often revealing suppressed traits or desires of the counterpart. Example: Tyler Durden from Fight Club.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Hopeful Outlander: From a different culture or world, they bring fresh perspectives and optimism, often challenging the status quo. Example: Wonder Woman in… Wonder Woman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mournful Avenger: Seeks vengeance for a personal loss, driven by sorrow and rage, often questioning their own motives along the way. Example: The Bride from Kill Bill.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Lighthearted Sage: Imparts wisdom or guidance, but does so with humor and a carefree demeanor. Example: Uncle Iroh from Avatar: The Last Airbender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Reclusive Genius: Exceptionally skilled or knowledgeable, but shuns society, often due to trauma or disdain for societal norms. Example: Dr. Robert Ford from Westworld.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Sentinel at the End: Guards the last barrier or threshold the protagonist must face, often providing the final challenge. Example: The Black Knight from Monty Python and the Holy Grail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Orphan Seeking Kin: Driven by a desire to find their true origins or family, their journey intertwines with larger events. Example: Elsa from Frozen.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Masked Avenger: Works in the shadows, hiding their identity as they seek justice or vengeance. Example: V from… V for Vendetta.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Wild Card: Unpredictable, with shifting loyalties or unclear motives, they add an element of uncertainty to the story. Example: Tactus from Red Rising.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Naive Idealist: Often young or inexperienced, they believe in the inherent good of the world, which might lead to both triumphs and tragedies. Example: Pip from Great Expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Brooding Loner: Haunted by their past, they prefer solitude but are often pulled into societal affairs against their will. Example: Jessica Jones from… the Jessica Jones series.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Resilient Survivor: Has undergone significant trauma, yet their journey is one of healing and overcoming. Example: Lisbeth Salander from The Girl with the Dragon Tattoo.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Curious Explorer: Driven by a thirst for knowledge or the unknown, they often embark on adventures into uncharted territories. Example: Sir John Huxley from The Lost World.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Playful Trickster: Relies on wit and cunning, often playing pranks or deceiving others, but not necessarily with malicious intent. Example: Puck from A Midsummer Night’s Dream.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Aging Warrior: Past their prime but with a wealth of experience, they often play mentor roles or seek one final grand adventure. Example: Master Roshi from Dragon Ball.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Benevolent Guide: Often has mystical or otherworldly knowledge, guiding the protagonist on their journey. Example: Mr. Miyagi from The Karate Kid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Outcast with a Secret: Shunned or misunderstood by society, they possess knowledge or abilities that become crucial to the plot. Example: Quasimodo from The Hunchback of Notre Dame.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Determined Inventor: Driven by innovation, they’re constantly creating, sometimes leading to beneficial discoveries or unintended consequences. Example: Doc Brown from Back to the Future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Cynic with a Hidden Heart: Appears jaded or sarcastic but eventually reveals deep-seated passion or kindness. Example: Dr. Gregory House from… House.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Guardian at the Crossroads: Protects a certain territory or object, determining who can pass or obtain it, often testing the protagonist’s worthiness. Example: The Sphinx from Greek mythology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Time-Tested Friend: Has been friends with another character for ages, providing a bridge to the past and unconditional support. Example: Sevro in Red Rising.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Wanderer with No Past: Arrives from nowhere, with no past that they’re willing to discuss, but plays a crucial role in events. Example: The Man With No Name from A Fistful of Dollars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Prophet of Doom: Predicts dire events or outcomes, often dismissed or misunderstood until their prophecies begin to come true. Example: Cassandra from Greek mythology.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Relentless Pursuer: Single-minded in their mission to hunt someone or something down, stopping at nothing to achieve their goal. Example: Javert from Les Misérables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Enthusiastic Amateur: Lacks professional skills or knowledge but makes up for it with passion and a can-do attitude. Example: Elle Woods from Legally Blonde.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Enigmatic Stranger: Mysterious and not fully understood, this character brings change, for better or worse. Example: Auri from The Name of the Wind.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Virtuous Outcast: Possesses a moral code but is excluded or shunned by mainstream society. Example: Jean Valjean from Les Misérables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Silent Observer: Watches and understands more than they let on, often revealing profound insights. Example: Nick Carraway from The Great Gatsby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Disguised Ruler: A leader or royalty in hiding, either for protection or to observe their people unnoticed. Example: King Richard in Robin Hood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dreamer Bound by Reality: Aspires for more than their circumstances allow, often leading to bittersweet outcomes. Example: Walter Mitty from The Secret Life of Walter Mitty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fallen Mentor: Once a guide or teacher, they’ve since lost their way, often needing redemption or serving as a warning. Example: Ben Kenobi from Star Wars.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ambiguous Ally: Their allegiance is unclear, keeping other characters (and the audience) guessing. Example: Severus Snape from Harry Potter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Pacifist Warrior: Skilled in combat but chooses non-violence, only fighting when absolutely necessary. Example: Aang from Avatar: The Last Airbender.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Altruistic Thief: Steals, but with noble intentions, often redistributing wealth or righting societal wrongs. Example: Robin Hood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Disillusioned Dreamer: Once held great ideals or dreams but faced setbacks, leading to a more cynical worldview. Example: Don Quixote from… Don Quixote.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Benevolent Conqueror: Seeks to expand their domain, but with the aim of bringing peace, order, or prosperity. Example: Cyrus the Great.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Broken Peacemaker: Strives for peace but has personal traumas or conflicts that they struggle with. Example: Desmond Doss from Hacksaw Ridge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Seeker of Forbidden Truths: Goes to great lengths to uncover truths that others believe should remain hidden or forgotten. Example: Robert Langdon from Angels &amp;amp; Demons.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Mournful Avenger: Seeks vengeance not out of anger, but out of sorrow for a personal loss. Example: Maximus from Gladiator.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Ethical Mercenary: Works for hire, but has a personal code that dictates who they will and won’t work for or what jobs they’ll accept. Example: Geralt of Rivia from The Witcher.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Tinkerer at the Crossroads: Always inventing or tweaking, their creations might bring about significant change or disaster. Example: Doc Brown from Back to the Future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Displaced Noble: Born to privilege but finds themselves in humble or challenging circumstances, often learning profound lessons. Example: Prince Edward from The Prince and the Pauper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Tormented Artist: Creates profound art but is plagued by personal demons or societal misunderstandings. Example: Vincent van Gogh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Echo from the Past: Returns from a bygone era or brings an old way of thinking into the present, challenging modern perspectives. Example: Captain America in The Avengers.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Defender of the Lost Cause: Continues to fight for a cause that most believe is already lost or futile. Example: Ned Stark from Game of Thrones.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Hidden Mastermind: Operates from the shadows, their influence felt but their identity and intentions concealed. Example: Keyser Söze from The Usual Suspects.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Star-Crossed Lovers: These characters are deeply in love but fated for tragedy, often due to external forces like feuding families, differing backgrounds, or insurmountable circumstances. Example: Romeo and Juliet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Loyal Retainer: Unwaveringly dedicated to another character, they provide support, often at great personal risk or sacrifice. Example: Alfred from Batman.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Forgotten Chronicler: Records events or truths that others overlook or choose to forget, often providing a different perspective on history. Example: Samwell Tarly from Game of Thrones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="archetypes," /><category term="characters" /><category term="writing," /><category term="characters," /><category term="archetypes" /><summary type="html">Here is a list of seventy-seven character archetypes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Judging a Book by it’s Cover</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/inspirational,/illustrations/2024/10/21/Judging-a-Book-by-its-Cover/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Judging a Book by it’s Cover" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/inspirational,/illustrations/2024/10/21/Judging-a-Book-by-its-Cover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/inspirational,/illustrations/2024/10/21/Judging-a-Book-by-its-Cover/">&lt;div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot; style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/images/kahknot.png&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-title=&quot;Kahknot&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img class=&quot;container post-image&quot; alt=&quot;Kahknot&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kahknot.png&quot; /&gt;

    &lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;container figure-caption&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: -16px !important; text-align: center; margin-bottom: 16px&quot;&gt;
        Kahknot
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a good solid look at the photo contained within this post. It is said that we judge books by their covers. So, with that being said, looking at that photo (yes it is AI generated) would you purchase this book without knowing that it is a fantasy book centered around a fledgling mage who wants to bring magic to the masses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of ALL of the two-thousand-four-hundred and ninety-three stories I have in my CardBuddy database, this cover has to be my favorite, hands down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, tell me, what would you do?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-the-back-of-the-book&quot;&gt;From the Back of the Book:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For centuries, the Armond family has lived in the shadows, guardians of an ancient and powerful secret. Their sprawling estate, hidden in the misty valleys of a remote mountain range, houses a vast underground laboratory where they craft potions capable of altering the very fabric of reality. Love, fortune, life, and health - all can be manipulated through their mystical elixirs. The family’s power comes at a price: an inviolable code of silence. For generations, the Armonds have sworn to keep magic hidden from the world, believing that its revelation would bring chaos and destruction. They operate through a network of trusted intermediaries, never revealing their true identities to their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kahknot Armond, a brilliant and idealistic young alchemist, chafes against these restrictions. She dreams of a world where magic can be used openly to benefit all of humanity. Her grandfather, Lias Armond, the stern patriarch of the family, vehemently opposes her views, leading to months of heated arguments that threaten to tear the family apart. Unbeknownst to Kahknot, her cousin and best friend Nykivi has been secretly recording their arguments and sharing them with a mysterious figure known only as The Seeker. Nykivi believes she’s protecting the family by exposing Kahknot’s dangerous ideas, but she’s unwittingly set in motion a chain of events that will change everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kahknot, frustrated by her family’s refusal to see reason, makes a fateful decision. Using a newly developed potion that temporarily nullifies magical detection, she sneaks into the family vault and steals the Armond Grimoire, an ancient tome containing their most powerful recipes. With this knowledge, she launches Armond’s Elixirs publicly, revealing the existence of magic to the world. The reaction is immediate and intense. Wonder and excitement sweep across the globe as people rush to experience the miraculous potions. However, fear and suspicion quickly follow. Religious leaders decry the elixirs as heretical abominations. Governments scramble to regulate this new and potentially destabilizing force. Criminal organizations see an opportunity for immense profit and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As chaos engulfs the world, Kahknot finds an unexpected ally in Dr. Ermelia Vance, a renowned scientist who sees the potential for combining magic and technology. Together, they begin working on a revolutionary project to create a sustainable, ethical system for distributing magical benefits to all of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sinister apothecary known as The Seeker is revealed to be Kahknot’s long-lost twin brother, Xaphoyr, who was stolen as an infant and raised by a rival magical family. Consumed by jealousy and a twisted desire for power, Xaphoyr kidnaps Kahknot, intending to extract her knowledge and destroy the Armond family. Nykivi, wracked with guilt over her unwitting role in Kahknot’s predicament, embarks on a perilous quest to save her cousin. She must navigate a world turned upside down by the revelation of magic, facing hostile government agents, religious zealots, and rival magical factions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During her journey, Nykivi discovers an ancient prophecy hidden within the family’s genealogy. It speaks of twin Armond heirs who will either bring about a golden age of magical harmony or plunge the world into eternal darkness. The prophecy’s fulfillment hinges on a choice that must be made at the moment of greatest peril. Nykivi races against time, gathering allies and unlocking her own latent magical abilities. She eventually confronts Xaphoyr in a spectacular magical duel atop a crumbling skyscraper. As the battle reaches its climax, Kahknot breaks free of her bonds and is faced with an impossible choice: save her brother or protect the Armond Grimoire from falling into the wrong hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment of clarity, Kahknot chooses compassion over power. She reaches out to Xaphoyr offering him forgiveness and a chance to reunite their fractured family. This act of love fulfills the positive aspect of the prophecy, causing a surge of magical energy that heals the rift between the siblings and stabilizes the chaotic magical energies threatening to tear the world apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath, the Armond family, now including Xaphoyr, works with world leaders and Dr. Vance to establish a new global order. Magic is carefully integrated into society, with the Armonds serving as teachers and guardians rather than secretive puppet masters. Kahknot and Nykivi, their bond stronger than ever, lead the charge in creating a magical education system that emphasizes responsibility and ethics alongside power. The story ends with a glimpse of the future: a world where magic and technology coexist harmoniously, and the Armond family stands proud as protectors of this new age of wonder and possibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="inspirational," /><category term="illustrations" /><category term="writing," /><category term="cover," /><category term="art" /><summary type="html">Kahknot</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Outline - The Mourning Path</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/outline/2024/10/21/An-Outline-The-Mourning-Path/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Outline - The Mourning Path" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/outline/2024/10/21/An-Outline-The-Mourning-Path</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/outline/2024/10/21/An-Outline-The-Mourning-Path/">&lt;p&gt;In keeping with my want to talk about grief, here’s an outline that should be placed within an outline to show the grieving process properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line with change (and change is the substance of story) is that it requires loss. Even when change is positive, we lose something of ourselves coping with its effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mourning Path:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Precipice: The precipice is where you’re standing as you learn about the death of someone dear to you. It is a place filled with so many different emotions that you hardly know who you are, much less begin to process them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Loss/The Hurt: Whether it’s a close friend, spouse, partner, parent, child, or other relative, the pain one feels immediately after the death of a loved one can feel overwhelming. You may experience waves of intense and very difficult emotions, ranging from profound sadness, emptiness, and despair to shock and numbness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Initial Shock: Shock is typically experienced as one of the first stages in the grief process, and eventually it wears off. For some, shock recedes very quickly. For others, shock lasts for hours or days. Everyone is different and there is no right or wrong way to experience shock.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Numbness: Some of us feel sad when someone dies. Some of us feel angry. But some of us feel nothing at all. Emotional numbness can be linked with a type of grief called ‘inhibited grief,’ which is characterized by suppressed emotions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Denial: Denial is the refusal to accept the facts of the loss, either consciously or unconsciously. If dealing with death is personal, there is a refusal to take necessary steps to prepare for death, such as a will.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Emotional Outbursts: You’re definitely upset, but more often than not, you’re not upset at who you think you’re upset at. Grief and emotional outbursts tend to walk hand in hand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Anger: Many people do in fact feel angry when someone we love dies. Angry at being abandoned, angry at the extent of the pain, angry that our life is changed, angry that managing grief feels difficult, and angry that the world suddenly feels different—empty, unsafe, or lonely. Swallowed feelings don’t disappear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Fear: If you search fear symptoms on the internet, you get a list of very similar feelings in both grief and fear. Grief feels like fear because it leaves you reeling in uncertainty. If you think about it, most of the things that we think give us a sense of certainty in our lives, do not. We assume that if we live right, eat right, take care of ourselves, and are loving and thoughtful, we will be rewarded and those we love will be kept safe. When the worst happens, we then question who we are, and where is God? What do I do? Where do I turn next? How do I move forward? Do I even want to move at all? Nothing makes sense and caring about anything seems fruitless. We don’t feel safe in our own skin. And we don’t know whom we can trust.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Search: It’s hard to explain this “search” to people who haven’t experienced it because it isn’t just a matter of looking around for the person and finding they’re not there. Instead, search, in this context, means doing all sorts of things to try and repair the physical attachment - like seeking out sights, sounds, smells, people, and places that remind you of the person. Sometimes you get so close that for a split second, you honestly think you’ve managed to cross the void. But then, once again, your loved one is gone. It’s like they’ve picked up the phone, said “hello”, and the signal cuts out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Disorganization: Just from a superficial point of view, the face of a grieving person can be pretty damn messy – bloodshot eyes, runny, red nose, puffy eyelids, red nose and other outward appearances that we might want to hide. Grief can also throw other physical aspects out of whack. An example: The house is in complete disarray.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Panic: Grief can make us feel like we’ve lost our sense of safety and control. It’s natural to feel panic or worried about what might happen next or even to worry that we might lose someone else in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Valley: The valley is where you’re sitting when you’re neck deep in the grief after losing someone dear to you. You can’t see a way out of it, and in most cases you have no interest in leaving in the first place.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Loneliness: Loneliness is a natural part of grief and it is one of the more trying aspects of accepting a loss. When a loved one dies, a hole is left that no one and nothing else can fill. It is as if no one else can know or understand. The intense and mixed feelings of grief can lead to separation and isolation from others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Guilt: Guilt can be a common yet complex emotion in grief. The truth is that we can feel guilty about so many things. Guilt does not always have to be rational to be real. That means even when we realize our guilt is not based on reality, we still may experience it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Isolation: Experiencing grief can be an isolating experience for many people. The only person who can truly understand your loss is you; nobody else knew your loved one in the same way you did, and no one knew them in the exact way you did.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Depression: The depression associated with grief is like being in an ongoing, heightened state of mourning that keeps you from healing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Hard Climb Out: The hard climb out is when you start to look past the grief that has all but consumed you, and you start to look at what life means and what life looks like beyond that grief.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Loss Adjustment: You know that you’ve reached this stage when you can do the following: Recognize the loss, react to the separation, recollect and re-experience, relinquish old attachments and readjust and reinvest in life.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Recovery Guilt: In recovery guilt, grievers tend to look at other people who have been grieving a similar loss or perhaps even the same loss, and sense that they are coping too well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Re-Entry Troubles: Once the effort is made to get back into the normal routine, the pain of loss makes it difficult to be as trusting and open as before the loss. Suspicion must be battled constantly. Friends and families are tested again and again.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Relationships: It’s not always easy to understand that it is possible to love and miss someone, while having room to be happy and involved with new people and new relationships.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Patterns: Most of our habituated behavior serves us well. Checking for traffic, when crossing a street, keeps us safe. Brushing our teeth and washing our hands promotes better health. The list is endless. Once that belief system and our habits are established, we follow them without a second thought. The fact is that these habits become such an integral part of who we are, that anything that doesn’t fall within them tends to receive an automatic critical response from us. This is all about changing old habits on how to deal with emotionally painful events and creating new ones that help you move through and beyond them. It’s about helping you discover those things that are incomplete in relationships and finding a way to let go of those painful feelings that you have stuffed inside. It’s not about forgetting the past, but rather being able to effectively deal with it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Hope: Gradually, the pain subsides and the world becomes bearable again. Hope sneaks through the cracks in the walls built up as protection against hurt. Energy is regained. The process of rebuilding seems possible.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The New Affirmations: The loss is accepted without bitterness. Death begins to give way to new life. Purpose is regained. A new, different reality is where life is to be lived.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Act of Helping Others: When someone in your life is dealing with a loss, you now intrinsically understand just what to expect as they go through the grieving process and you can help them get through it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="outline" /><category term="writing," /><category term="outline" /><summary type="html">In keeping with my want to talk about grief, here’s an outline that should be placed within an outline to show the grieving process properly.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Five-Hundred and Twenty-Seven Potential Character Names</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/names,/writing/2024/10/21/My-Name-List/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Five-Hundred and Twenty-Seven Potential Character Names" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/names,/writing/2024/10/21/%20My-Name-List</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/names,/writing/2024/10/21/My-Name-List/">&lt;p&gt;Every author I know has a running list of potential character names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s mine, in alphabetical order. Please note, that my name list does not contain average or popular names. I prefer VERY unique names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be editing this post at some point to include proper pronunciations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, here’s my current list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aalailey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abaheith&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abisha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Acton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addisol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adrist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adyxavier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aerith&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahdiss&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahinoam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahleiphur&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahlulbayt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahran&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahrayah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahtillya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ahyoka&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aidrah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ailbhe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ainul&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Akhirah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Albornoz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aldus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aleel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alexito&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alhalramain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alignyah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alishelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alji&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allillieyah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alondra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aloris&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alparslan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alsea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alvara&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alvonne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amalraine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Andaiya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angham&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aniabae&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aniam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Annielar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anntennetah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Araminat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Araujo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arbesa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ardeth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arsema&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arshan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arshiya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arthal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arthit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arunreeji&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arvada&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arvlyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arza&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ashellika&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ashpia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ashtoreth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ashy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Athaliah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Athalie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Athalye&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Atrendai&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aubryn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Audrux&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autzen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avaeleigh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aven&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Averyan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avguštin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aviah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avivah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avonlei&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AxIra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ayalanna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Aylul&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Azucena&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Azwahjel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Balinor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barnabette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Barne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Batikh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beaukannan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Beleila&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Belvy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bersabe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bhanríon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bhasin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Branita&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Breavenah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brekken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Briseadh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brudjet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buckhanan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Byrode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bélizaire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Callixte&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Canzalie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cardin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cavid&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cawnawyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charlevoix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chasen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chigyantsev&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chillisa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chilliskah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chillista&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chypre&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cloyce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Colyntari&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cuevas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cyvantae&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dadanir&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daefyd&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daindreth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dalisay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Danulz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daryna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dassie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daudilee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daveigh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dayeena&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deadreiel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dehontjihgwaes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dehrmot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deirdre&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dejazu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delgerbayar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delimar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deogo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deorr&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Derlahn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deujardine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;DeVaal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Devraxshe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dieter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dorthula&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dovie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drakota&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dranette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Duacynt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dutch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Déanfardúacht&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Déantoir&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eann&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eccey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ever&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Egwene&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Einar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elayn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eleeī&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elhana&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elisheba&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eloah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elphaba&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elthan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embriella&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emnyt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ennhanah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enntanettah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enzoc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eodin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eogan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Erixon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eshaa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estefany&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Estrah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Euri&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Euwynn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evabeth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evadne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evalee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evianca&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Evrah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eylarrah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eyelaura&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Eyezra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ezcher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ezwatti&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ferol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fiadh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gaysah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gehrig&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getenet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getnic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getnyt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gevherhan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gheorghe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gillus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ginejko&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Guerlain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gwenjalen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gwyninn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haimalyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Halseth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hamadali&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hannalah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Harbogon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Haxel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heathyr&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Helleel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hialeah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hiraani&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hodac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hodax&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hounna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hovanec&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ilayda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Illin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ilroi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iltena&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inglynd&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ipkueyeyah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Islwyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iwaleelo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Iyanla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaloyd&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jamorelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Janneje&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jarkayla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jarkaylee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaspin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jaxsac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jehoaddan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jephte&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeshari&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jetmir&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeudi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jevyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jheene&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jhessye&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jinapher&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joahnseae&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jodah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joeleette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joella&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joniece&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jordanne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jorjon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jover&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jovie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Joysine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jroanna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jrocorik&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Junyi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juré&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juztyce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Juztyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kabergeron&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kadavah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kadulyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kaibree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kajouji&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kaleste&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kalestina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kallikrien&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kalyatra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kamissa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karmeanne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karwryn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kasasi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kashton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kataifi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kazley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keightley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Keiran&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kersea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kersean&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khadlaj&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khadtherine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khady&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khaiwryn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khaiwrynah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Khanat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kharlyle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Klhutlun&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kodiak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kohrmac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Koreci&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kvaltin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kyan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kylye&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lahjim&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laird&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lares&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Larkin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lattafa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laurerahn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lauriano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lavalle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leanner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leesbit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leinonen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leithreas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lelleann&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lesley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lieja&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lillianette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lingzi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linysee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lirentity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lisza&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lizeth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loucerahla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lujane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lydus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lysandar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Macady&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maclend&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Macxelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maelora&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Magen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mahalath&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maitlis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maiyhan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mallacht&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marghe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Margus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mariangel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marsaili&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Martine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Martlet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Masodah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maxel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maxton&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mayci&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maziah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mehrnaz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Melynn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meradys&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meris&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Messody&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mezhgorye&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Miayla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Michaely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Miciso&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mihirimah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Minyekah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Moniza&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muirgheal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Muriel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Myrleigha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naeem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Namunzul&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Narloni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nashar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Naziera&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nazlee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neligh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nevellin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nezerhat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nicarico&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nicolawsen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nifemi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ninian&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Niviarsiaq&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nixzmary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nizani&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nkem&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noalei&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nouriah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nytomt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nyx&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NíMaura&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Odison&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ogemma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Olanick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ollard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onadyne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onagh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onarak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orlagh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Orsolya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Osric&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ozolin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paila&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parkaire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pashlee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Penelee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Penelen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phadraig&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phaimany&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pholia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Piirainen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pomahac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ponch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preslaysa&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Primala&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ptoughneigh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Puck&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pynnelopeigh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Qayarq&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quetzalli&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quvenzhané&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radabah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rahmani&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rainin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Razleine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reahtae&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reigelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhaknotzah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhetchelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rhysandor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Riggan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rogazah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rosamund&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roshnee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roucankour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rowaha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruoxi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruusha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ruxel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ryelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rymzlin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sabrehna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sailynne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Samra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Samyle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sarael&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sarkisian&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sarm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Savei&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seath&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seayonna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Selty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Severse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seward&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shadrack&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shaidyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shainey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shandraly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sharge&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sharlow&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sheynnis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shihadeh&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shouleen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shouleine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sinjin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sistani&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sitha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slaine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sloanne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sobelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socorro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soirée&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Solene&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sonica&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sorcha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Soshal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sparrel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stori&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stván&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suehme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Suesam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sulla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sushila&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swansea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sybeth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Synorah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Síle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tabarruj&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tadeo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Takamyn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Takoda&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taliesin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tananarive&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tannaz&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tawhiao&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Teydah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thayo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Theodorou&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thyra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tiahuia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tiernanen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tinashe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tirzah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomiris&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travee&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Treaven&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trebayvaughn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tynion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Typhi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ulrayna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ulrayne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uwan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vadim&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vaeomi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Varrtha&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Veranique&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wafaleicia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wendla&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Witten&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrexam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrynji&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wyladene&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wynent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wynsie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wyr&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xael&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xiomara&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xiran&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xshaeta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xyelle&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Xzya&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yael&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yaryna&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yerushalmi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yinter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yooran&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yousafzai&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yvie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zahava&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zakkai&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zandstra&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zelyse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zhuri&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zihnic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Zuhailyn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="names," /><category term="writing" /><category term="writing," /><category term="names" /><summary type="html">Every author I know has a running list of potential character names.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Story Beat of the Day - A Rotund Helping of Grief</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/individual/story/beat,/seasoning/2024/10/21/The-Beat-of-the-Day-A-Rotund-Helping-of-Grief/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Story Beat of the Day - A Rotund Helping of Grief" /><published>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/individual/story/beat,/seasoning/2024/10/21/The-Beat-of-the-Day-A-Rotund-Helping-of-Grief</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/individual/story/beat,/seasoning/2024/10/21/The-Beat-of-the-Day-A-Rotund-Helping-of-Grief/">&lt;p&gt;I want to talk about grief today. So, both the beat of the day and the outline is going to circle around grief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something happens that causes immense grief for the protagonist and his group. This could involve the disillusionment of a relationship, someone physically leaving their group, a negative change of physical, mental, emotional or sexual health, losing something vital to their journey, someone dying, having to leave someplace where they’ve found safety, losing trust in someone, imprisonment, or a loss of faith. This folder can be placed multiple times in the same section or multiple sections, depending on the need too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="individual" /><category term="story" /><category term="beat," /><category term="seasoning" /><category term="writing," /><category term="individual" /><category term="story" /><category term="beat," /><category term="seasoning" /><summary type="html">I want to talk about grief today. So, both the beat of the day and the outline is going to circle around grief.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Beat of the Day - Actions and Lessons</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/individual/story/beat,/seasoning/2024/09/30/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Actions-and-Lessons/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Beat of the Day - Actions and Lessons" /><published>2024-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-09-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/individual/story/beat,/seasoning/2024/09/30/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Actions-and-Lessons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/blog/writing,/individual/story/beat,/seasoning/2024/09/30/The-Beat-of-the-Day-Actions-and-Lessons/">&lt;p&gt;The “Action Lesson” scene is where the protagonist attempts something, it goes horribly wrong, and they must then learn where they went wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mentor character is the only one who can teach them this. It is the most direct a mentor can usually be when it comes to espousing the book’s themes and the truth, especially when it is merely the mentor sharing wisdom rather than them acting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These scenes typically work best when failure is an emotional experience for the protagonist, and that failure allows them to believe, accept, or understand a Truth that they could not before, rather than it being a case of them just not having heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Relying on these scenes too much can come across as heavy-handed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- signature --&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: block; align-content: center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img style=&quot;width:320px; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/kojika-signature.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>K°</name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="individual" /><category term="story" /><category term="beat," /><category term="seasoning" /><category term="writing," /><category term="individual" /><category term="story" /><category term="beat," /><category term="seasoning" /><summary type="html">The “Action Lesson” scene is where the protagonist attempts something, it goes horribly wrong, and they must then learn where they went wrong.</summary></entry></feed>